<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Generated by Site-Server v6.0.0-26449-26449 (http://www.squarespace.com) on Mon, 19 Oct 2020 02:54:38 GMT
--><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://www.rssboard.org/media-rss" version="2.0"><channel><title>Policies - Imam Andrews</title><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/</link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 07:52:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><language>en-AU</language><generator>Site-Server v6.0.0-26449-26449 (http://www.squarespace.com)</generator><description><![CDATA[<p>Our positive plan will deliver for every Victorian, in every corner of our state.</p>
<p>It will make sure our kids reach their full potential, give patients the care and dignity they deserve, and get people home sooner and safer.</p>
<p>It’s a plan that will keep creating jobs and give a helping hand to hardworking families.</p>
<p>Labor’s plan will deliver for all Victorians.</p>]]></description><item><title>BUILDING A BETTER ARMENIAN COMMUNITY CENTRE</title><category>Fairness</category><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 08:00:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/building-a-better-armenian-community-centre</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf7b1bc4fa51a471a508823</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>A re-elected Andrews Labor Government will provide $35,000 towards an upgrade of the Armenian Community Centre in Mulgrave. </p><p>Labor’s funding will go towards an upgrade of the Centre’s carpark and other facilities, strengthening community ties by allowing more people to visit the centre. </p><p>The Centre is used for events, festivals and activities, as well as providing a dedicated space for locals with Armenian heritage to come together and celebrate their culture and traditions.</p><p>As part of the <em>Victorian Budget 2018/19</em>, the Andrews Labor Government delivered vital funding to improve facilities for local multicultural communities, including a $17.1 million boost to Multicultural Community Infrastructure Program. </p><p>Only Labor recognises the contribution of our proud Armenian communities and only Labor is willing to make the investments that really matter.</p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Premier of Victoria and Member for Mulgrave Daniel Andrews</strong></p><p><em>“Our Armenian communities make a proud contribution to Victoria and I’m proud to offer this support.”</em></p><p><em>“With these investments, we’ll will make sure that the Armenian Community Centre has the facilities it needs to keep serving Armenian Victorians for years to come.”</em></p>


	<a href="" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" >download the media release</a>

<p><br></p>]]></description><media:content type="image/png" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542960025172-MWP1VD6VZH4NK8F5O8AS/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmrMDYraMJMCQwFxTSOIP7LpSBEQpA-g5k6VTjWbSuadHJq0dp98hg5AZvIaPb3DoM/DA.png?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">BUILDING A BETTER ARMENIAN COMMUNITY CENTRE</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>COOKING UP A WIN FOR OAK PARK SOCCER CLUB</title><category>Fairness</category><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 07:49:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/cooking-up-a-win-for-oak-park-soccer-club</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf7afe84d7a9c8adb0f6138</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Families in Oak Park will be able to come together and celebrate victory on the pitch with a re-elected Andrews Labor Government to provide $50,000 for the Oak Park Soccer Club. </p><p>Oak Park Soccer Club is a proud, predominately Kurdish community club with men’s, women’s and kid’s teams.</p><p>Labor’s funding will go towards an upgrade of the club’s kitchen facilities, encouraging more community events and strengthening community ties. </p><p>With these upgrades from Labor, local clubs – and this proud, local community – will have the great sporting and community facilities they deserve. </p><p>As part of the Victorian Budget 2018/19, the Andrews Labor Government delivered vital funding to improve facilities for local multicultural communities, including a $17.1 million boost to the Multicultural Community Infrastructure Program. </p><p>Only Labor recognises the contribution of our proud Kurdish communities and only Labor is willing to make the investments that really matter.</p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Minister for Multicultural Affairs Robin Scott</strong></p><p><em>“Our state’s diversity is our greatest asset, and this funding from Labor will make sure that our Kurdish community can come together in an active, healthy and supportive way.”</em></p><p><em>““A re-elected Labor Government will make sure that Oak Park has the sporting and community facilities it needs.”</em></p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Member for Pascoe Vale Lizzie Blandthorn </strong></p><p><em>“Our Kurdish communities make a proud contribution to Victoria and I’m proud to offer this support.”</em></p><p><em>"Cooking and sharing traditional food is a big part of Kurdish culture. We'll make sure the Oak Park Soccer Club has the facilities it needs to fully celebrate its vibrant and diverse community spirit."</em></p>


	<a href="" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" >Download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542959231313-DLGH0GQ5NY7NQF4GXOX2/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/edoardo-busti-413350-unsplash.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">COOKING UP A WIN FOR OAK PARK SOCCER CLUB</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>PROVIDING GOOD, FRESH FOOD TO MORE FAMILIES IN NEED </title><category>Fairness</category><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 07:27:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/providing-good-fresh-food-to-more-families-in-need</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf7ab81758d46cefdb9b445</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>More struggling families will have access to good, fresh food, with a re-elected Andrews Labor Government to provide $2.5 million to support FareShare. </p><p>The funding will allow FareShare to focus on delivering more meals to needy people across the state.  </p><p>FareShare runs Australia’s largest charity kitchens.  Since 2000, they have worked with businesses to collect their surplus food and turn it into free nutritious meals for people right across Victoria. </p><p>Last year FareShare chefs and volunteers turned donated food into 1.2 million nutritious meals in their Abbotsford facility.  Their meals are distributed for free to hundreds of local charities. </p><p>While most of the meals are distributed to charities across metropolitan Melbourne, 30 percent of meals are distributed to groups in regional Victoria. </p><p>Eight hundred people from all walks of life regularly volunteer at our Abbotsford kitchen - and they have 1,500 people on a waiting list keen to become regular volunteers.   </p><p>Each year 2,500 secondary school children and 3,500 corporate volunteers also help cook meals, giving back to the community under the guidance of FareShare’s professional chefs and staff. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to the Minister for Education James Merlino </strong></p><p><em>“Local families should never have to go without fresh food. That’s why we’ll make sure FareShare can deliver more food to more people across our community.” </em></p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Member for Richmond Richard Wynne </strong></p><p><em> “Sometimes life can hit you hard. Labor will make sure that when times are tough, families can rely on FareShare’s fundamental support.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-Providing-Good-Fresh-Food-To-More-Families-In-Need.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542958327309-Z2XA4WGI0XA6VQP3DHKC/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kN_ZoNdj1kv_gIvm4zjH76N7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z4YTzHvnKhyp6Da-NYroOW3ZGjoBKy3azqku80C789l0jG2lbcDYBOeMi4OFSYem8AelHsSihC3tfiYK1eHEM7W3AVjJQSBul2wE-DqW7dygg/Fareshare-003.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1500" height="1072"><media:title type="plain">PROVIDING GOOD, FRESH FOOD TO MORE FAMILIES IN NEED</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>THE LIBERALS' PLAN TO SELL OFF YOUR WATER </title><category>Fairness</category><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 07:22:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/the-liberals-plan-to-sell-off-your-water</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf7a9624ae237e15d340eff</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Liberal Leader Matthew Guy has confirmed his plan to sell off Victoria’s water to big corporations to help fund his budget black hole.  </p><p>Treasurer Tim Pallas today released disturbing new information showing that Victorians will pay more for their water under Matthew Guy’s plan.  </p><p>Every time the Liberals privatise essential services, it’s hardworking Victorian families that pay the price.  </p><p>When former Liberal Premier Jeff Kennett privatised our power – every Victorian’s power bill went up.  </p><p>Now they want to privatise our water, and could sell these assets to the same big corporations that are now in control of our power. </p><p>We know what that means: every time you turn on your tap, every time you have a shower, every time you flush the toilet – you will pay more. </p><p>And under the Liberals’ plan, Victorian families will pay more for 50 long years.  </p><p>The Liberals will slug Victorians because they need to fund the massive, $43 billion budget black hole they have revealed in their costings.  </p><p>They’ve promised more than $54.3 billion in infrastructure projects, yet have only funded $11.3 billion of them. </p><p>The Liberals have ruled out borrowing, tax increases and value capture – meaning they can only pay for their commitments by sacking workers, closing schools and hospitals, and selling off our water, making Victorians pay more. </p><p>Only Labor has a fully-costed, fully-funded plan that delivers for all Victorians. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Treasurer Tim Pallas </strong></p><p><em>“Make no mistake – this is the Liberals promising to privatise our water system.” </em></p><p><em>“Under the Liberals, every time you turn on your tap, every time you have a shower, every time you flush the toilet – you will pay more. And you will pay more for 50 years” </em></p><p><em>“Handing Victoria’s water assets over to big corporations would hurt Victorian families and it’s all to fund the Liberals’ budget black hole.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-The-Liberals-Plan-To-Sell-Off-Your-Water.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">download the media release</a>




	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/WATER-PRIVATISATION-FACT-SHEET-FINAL.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">download the fact sheet</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542957717783-V9E5TXYV10PT07US02Z9/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/water.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">THE LIBERALS' PLAN TO SELL OFF YOUR WATER</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>MORE SUPPORT FOR WOMEN FLEEING FAMILY VIOLENCE </title><category>Fairness</category><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 07:13:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/more-support-for-women-fleeing-family-violence</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf7a812575d1f90eb6bf873</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Victims of family violence who suffer financially at the hands of perpetrators will have access to new specially trained financial counsellors, under a re-elected Andrews Labor Government. </p><p>The Andrews Labor Government has already taken action to help combat financial abuse as part of its record investment to address our state’s number one law and order issue, delivering 10 new financial counsellors to make it easier for women escaping violence to access this important advice. </p><p>But there’s more to do – that’s why Labor will invest $4.6 million over four years to double the number of financial counsellors, providing an additional 10 full-time specialist family violence financial counsellors to help victim survivors in our state.  </p><p>The financial counsellors will help those in abusive relationships by negotiating with creditors and debt collectors, helping to protect assets from repossession and helping victims access financial hardship programs. </p><p>Only Labor will implement all 227 recommendations from the Royal Commission into Family Violence. The Liberals have refused, saying they would consider the “financial impost” of these lifesaving recommendations. It beggars belief that anyone could say that protecting women and children from violence is a financial impost. </p><p>Labor has invested $2.6 billion to stop family violence, more than any government in Australian history, including $100 million to prevent family violence before it starts. </p><p>The rollout of the additional financial counsellors will begin in 2019. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Minister for the Prevention of Family Violence Natalie Hutchins </strong></p><p> <em>“No woman should be trapped in a violent and abusive relationship because they don’t have the financial support or tools to escape.” </em></p><p><em>“Family violence can take on many forms – this will give women the advice and information they need to keep themselves and their children safe.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-More-Support-For-Women-Fleeing-Family-Violence.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">Download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/png" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542957196905-OJAY8KVZS3IH1EWITJXF/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmrMDYraMJMCQwFxTSOIP7LpSBEQpA-g5k6VTjWbSuadHJq0dp98hg5AZvIaPb3DoM/FV.png?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">MORE SUPPORT FOR WOMEN FLEEING FAMILY VIOLENCE</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR GEELONG STUDENTS </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:54:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/free-school-lunches-and-breakfasts-for-geelong-students</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf7a3500ebbe88c33806af5</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>More students in Geelong will be able to learn on a full stomach with a re-elected Andrews Labor Government to expand the school breakfast program and as providing free school lunches to 1,000 schools across the state.  </p><p>One in seven kids arrive at school with an empty stomach, making it hard for them to pay attention in class and get the most out of their education. </p><p>That’s why the Andrews Labor Government launched School Breakfast Clubs, which provides 50,000 free breakfasts to 500 Victorian primary schools every week, but there is more to do.  </p><p>Already across Greater Geelong, 133,000 breakfasts have been delivered as part of more than 6 million served across the state.  </p><p>Labor will expand this into a new program that will serve up a free, healthy breakfast and lunch to students in need at 1,000 Victorian Government primary and secondary schools every school day. </p><p>It is estimated that around 10 per cent of children who attend breakfast clubs also come to school with nothing packed for lunch. Often staff will pay for lunch for kids to make sure they have something to eat.  </p><p>The new lunch program will mainly consist of sandwiches, soup, fruit and vegetables. As with the School Breakfast Clubs, Labor will work with Foodbank to include locally sourced food.  </p><p>In contrast, the former Liberal government cut the Education Maintenance Allowance, which went towards supporting local breakfast clubs. All this did was hurt students.  Victorians recently saw what could be expected under the Liberals, with the Morrison Government threatening funding cuts for the Foodbank Program.  </p><p>In addition to introducing school lunches, Labor will also provide school holiday backpacks with breakfast supplies to students in need and deliver a series of cooking masterclasses at 100 schools to share nutritional and meal preparation advice and information with families who are struggling.  This will help ensure that even outside school hours, kids are getting the healthy diet they need to be their best.  </p><p>Research has shown that since Labor’s School Breakfast Program started, nine out of ten teachers have seen improved student concentration, while six out of ten teachers have noted improved attendance.  </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Premier Daniel Andrews </strong></p><p><em>“The previous government cut Free Fruit Friday, leaving thousands of kids hungry and that tells Victorians everything they need to know about the Liberal’s priorities.”   </em></p><p><em>“If they are given the chance we know they’ll cut school programs again – cuts to breakfast clubs, cuts to the school uniform program and cuts to helping kids go on school camps and excursions.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Member for Geelong Christine Couzens </strong></p><p><em>“We can’t expect kids to concentrate in class on an empty stomach. That’s why we set up free School Breakfast Clubs - and that is why we will expand the program to provide two square meals a day to kids who need it.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Member for Bellarine Lisa Neville  </strong></p><p><em>“Labor wants to see every child reach their full potential. That’s why we’ll expand this program to the families that need it most.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Member for Lara John Eren  </strong></p><p><em>“Sadly there are some kids who come to school without eating and that has a big impact on how they learn. Expanding this program will only help more kids focus in class.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for South Barwon Darren Cheeseman  </strong></p><p><em>“The contrast couldn’t be clearer – the Liberals cut the programs our students need, and Labor gets on with expanding them.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-Free-School-Lunches-And-Breakfasts-For-Geelong-Students.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">Download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542956035698-Q7VO88OCIJOVPVKRDC33/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Breakfasts-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR GEELONG STUDENTS</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR LOCAL BASS STUDENTS </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:45:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/free-school-lunches-and-breakfasts-for-local-bass-students</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf7a0de40ec9ad4338a6c64</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>More local students will learn on a full stomach with a re-elected Andrews Labor Government to expand the school breakfast program and provide free school lunches to 1,000 schools across the state.  </p><p>One in seven kids arrive at school with an empty stomach, making it hard for them to pay attention in class and get the most out of their education. </p><p>That’s why the Andrews Labor Government launched School Breakfast Clubs, which provide 50,000 free breakfasts to 500 Victorian primary schools every week, but there is more to do.  </p><p>Across the Bass Coast Shire more than 95,000 school breakfasts have been delivered over the last four years, with more than 75,000 served across Cardinia Shire Council. </p><p>Labor will expand this into a new program that will serve up a free, healthy breakfast and lunch to students in need at 1,000 Victorian Government primary and secondary schools every school day. </p><p>It is estimated that around 10 per cent of children who attend breakfast clubs also come to school with nothing packed for lunch. Often staff will pay for lunch for kids to make sure they have something to eat.  </p><p>The new lunch program will mainly consist of sandwiches, soup, fruit and vegetables. As with to the School Breakfast Clubs, Labor will work with Foodbank to include locally sourced food.  </p><p>In contrast, the former Liberal government cut the Education Maintenance Allowance, which went towards supporting local breakfast clubs. All this did was hurt students.  Victorians recently saw what could be expected under the Liberals, with the Morrison Government threatening funding cuts for the Foodbank Program.  </p><p>In addition to introducing school lunches, Labor will also provide school holiday backpacks with breakfast supplies to students in need and deliver a series of cooking masterclasses at 100 schools to share nutritional and meal preparation advice and information with families who are struggling.  This will help make sure that even outside school hours, kids are getting the healthy diet they need to be their best.  </p><p>Research has shown that since Labor’s School Breakfast Clubs started, nine out of ten teachers have seen improved student concentration, while six out of ten teachers have noted improved attendance and more than eight out of ten teachers said they now had better relationships with their students. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Minister for Education James Merlino </strong></p><p><em>“When the Liberals cut Free Fruit Friday, leaving thousands of Victorian kids hungry, it said everything you need to know about their agenda.” </em></p><p><em>“If given the chance we know they’ll cut school programs again – cuts to breakfast clubs, cuts to school uniform support and cuts to helping kids go on school camps and excursions.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for Bass Jordan Crugnale  </strong></p><p><em>“Kids can’t be their best on an empty tummy – that’s why we set up free School Breakfast Clubs – and that is why Labor will make sure kids in need get two square meals a day.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for Gembrook Michael Galea </strong></p><p><em>“School Breakfast Clubs have served up millions of breakfasts to Victorian students around the state, and teachers are seeing the enormous difference it makes in class.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-Free-School-Lunches-And-Breakfasts-For-Local-Bass-Students.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542955521827-UXO2N2BRHGKI0YUICUHT/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Breakfasts-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR LOCAL BASS STUDENTS</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR CENTRAL VICTORIAN STUDENTS</title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:39:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/free-school-lunches-and-breakfasts-for-central-victorian-students</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf79f4589858391639bc9e8</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>More Central Goldfields students will learn on a full stomach with a re-elected Andrews Labor Government to expand the school breakfast program and provide free school lunches to 1,000 schools across the state.  </p><p>One in seven kids arrive at school with an empty stomach, making it hard for them to pay attention in class and get the most out of their education. </p><p>That’s why the Andrews Labor Government launched School Breakfast Clubs, which provide 50,000 free breakfasts to 500 Victorian primary schools every week, but there is more to do.  </p><p>More than 185,000 school breakfasts have already been delivered across Greater Bendigo in the last four years, with more than 57,000 across Central Goldfields, more than 26,000 in Mount Alexander Shire Council and more than 73,000 across Loddon Shire Council.  </p><p>Labor will expand this into a new program that will serve up a free, healthy breakfast and lunch to students in need at 1,000 Victorian Government primary and secondary schools every school day. </p><p>It is estimated that around 10 per cent of children who attend breakfast clubs also come to school with nothing packed for lunch. Often staff will pay for lunch for kids to make sure they have something to eat.  </p><p>The new lunch program will mainly consist of sandwiches, soup, fruit and vegetables. Similarly, to the School Breakfast Clubs, Labor will work with Foodbank to include locally sourced food.  </p><p>In contrast, the former Liberal government cut the Education Maintenance Allowance, which went towards supporting local breakfast clubs. All this did was hurt students.  Victorians recently saw what could be expected under the Liberals, with the Morrison Liberal Government threatening funding cuts for the Foodbank Program.  </p><p>In addition to introducing school lunches, Labor will also provide school holiday backpacks with breakfast supplies to students in need and deliver a series of cooking masterclasses at 100 schools to share nutritional and meal preparation advice and information with families who are struggling.  This will help make sure that even outside school hours, kids are getting the healthy diet they need to be their best.  </p><p>Research has shown that since Labor’s School Breakfast Program started, nine out of ten teachers have seen improved student concentration, while six out of ten teachers have noted improved attendance and more than eight out of ten teachers said they now had better relationships with their students. </p><p>Quotes attributable to Minister for Regional Development Jaala Pulford  </p><p>“When the Liberals cut Free Fruit Friday, leaving thousands of Victorian kids hungry, it spoke volumes about their agenda.   </p><p>“Make no mistake, if they are given the chance they’ll cut school programs again – cuts to breakfast clubs, to the school uniform program and to helping kids go on school camps and excursions.” </p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Member for Bendigo East Jacinta Allan  </strong></p><p><em>“By ensuring every student has everything they need to be their best, Labor is making sure no child is left behind.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Member for Bendigo West Maree Edwards  </strong></p><p><em> “Our School Breakfast Clubs are making a profound difference to local kids, local families and local schools. But under the Liberals this vital program will be on the chopping block.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for Ripon Sarah De Santis  </strong></p><p><em>“Teachers have told us School Breakfast Clubs are making an enormous difference. A re-elected Labor government will make sure even more kids in need can benefit.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-Free-School-Lunches-And-Breakfasts-For-Central-Victorian-Students.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" >download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542955142650-4XA2LOLVFVFVXGI1OWKZ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Breakfasts-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR CENTRAL VICTORIAN STUDENTS</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR GIPPSLAND STUDENTS </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:33:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/free-school-lunches-and-breakfasts-for-gippsland-students</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf79ece40ec9ad4338a5c9e</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>More Gippsland students will learn on a full stomach with a re-elected Andrews Labor Government to expand the school breakfast program and provide free school lunches to 1,000 schools across the state.  </p><p>One in seven kids arrive at school with an empty stomach, making it hard for them to pay attention in class and get the most out of their education. </p><p>That’s why the Andrews Labor Government launched School Breakfast Clubs, which provides 50,000 breakfast to 500 Victorian primary schools every week, but there is more to do.  </p><p>We have already delivered more than 730,000 school breakfasts across Latrobe, Wellington, Baw Baw, South Gippsland and East Gippsland council areas over the last fours years. </p><p>Labor will expand this into a new program that will serve up a free, healthy breakfast and lunch to students in need at 1,000 Victorian Government primary and secondary schools every school day. </p><p>It is estimated that around 10 per cent of children who attend breakfast clubs also come to school with nothing packed for lunch. Often staff will pay for lunch for kids to make sure they have something to eat.  </p><p>The new lunch program will mainly consist of sandwiches, soup, fruit and vegetables. As with to the School Breakfast Clubs, Labor will work with Foodbank to include locally sourced food.  </p><p>This expansion is on top of Labor’s recent commitment to establish a new Foodbank Hub in Morwell. These new food hubs will expand Foodbank’s critical work, extending its fresh food supply to almost 100,000 families and creating new local jobs. </p><p>In contrast, the former Liberal government cut the Education Maintenance Allowance, which went towards supporting local breakfast clubs. All this did was hurt students.  Victorians recently saw what could be expected under the Liberals, with the Morrison Government threatening funding cuts for the Foodbank Program.  </p><p>In addition to introducing school lunches, Labor will also provide school holiday backpacks with breakfast supplies to students in need and deliver a series of cooking masterclasses at 100 schools to share nutritional and meal preparation advice and information with families who are struggling.  This will help ensure that even outside school hours, kids are getting the healthy diet they need to be their best.  </p><p>Research has shown that since Labor’s School Breakfast Program started, nine out of ten teachers have seen improved student concentration, while six out of ten teachers have noted improved attendance and more than eight out of ten teachers said they now had better relationships with their students. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Minister for Education James Merlino </strong></p><p><em>“When the Liberals cut Free Fruit Friday, leaving thousands of Victorian kids hungry, it showed everything you need to know about their priorities. </em></p><p><em>“If they are given the chance they’ll cut school programs again – cuts to breakfast clubs, cuts to school uniform support and cuts to helping kids go on school camps and excursions.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Member for Northern Victoria Harriet Shing  </strong></p><p><em>The contrast couldn’t be clearer – the Liberals will cut and close, while Labor will support local students.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for Morwell Mark Richards   </strong></p><p><em>“No one wants to see a child struggle through an entire school day with nothing to eat. That’s why we will invest in two square meals for kids who need it.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-Free-School-Lunches-And-Breakfasts-For-Gippsland-Students.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542954800800-YU20W35B18RS3CERZHI6/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Breakfasts-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR GIPPSLAND STUDENTS</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR NORTH EAST STUDENTS </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:21:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/free-school-lunches-and-breakfasts-for-north-east-students</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf79bc3562fa7c95dc8bbd6</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>More North East Victorian students will be able to learn on a full stomach with a re-elected Andrews Labor Government to expand the school breakfast program and provide free school lunches to 1,000 schools across the state.  </p><p>One in seven kids arrive at school with an empty stomach, making it hard for them to pay attention in class and get the most out of their education. </p><p>That’s why the Andrews Labor Government launched School Breakfast Clubs, which provides 50,000 free breakfasts to 500 Victorian primary schools every week, but there is more to do.  </p><p>Across North East Victoria we have seen thousands of school breakfasts delivered, including: 183,000 in Greater Shepparton, 10,000 in Strathbogie, 92,000 in Moira, 33,000 in Benalla, 44,000 in Wangaratta, 17,000 in Indigo, 12,000 in Alpine, 26,000 in Wodonga, and 15,000 in Towong. </p><p>Labor will expand this into a new program that will serve up a free, healthy breakfast and lunch to students in need at 1,000 Victorian Government primary and secondary schools every school day. </p><p>It is estimated that around 10 per cent of children who attend breakfast clubs also come to school with nothing packed for lunch. Often staff will pay for lunch for kids to make sure they have something to eat.  </p><p>The new lunch program will mainly consist of sandwiches, soup, fruit and vegetables. As with the School Breakfast Clubs, Labor will work with Foodbank to include locally sourced food.  </p><p>In contrast, the former Liberal government cut the Education Maintenance Allowance, which went towards supporting local breakfast clubs. All this did was hurt students.  Victorians recently saw what could be expected under the Liberals, with the Morrison Government threatening funding cuts for the Foodbank Program.  </p><p>In addition to introducing school lunches, Labor will also provide school holiday backpacks with breakfast supplies to students in need and deliver a series of cooking masterclasses at 100 schools to share nutritional and meal preparation advice and information with families who are struggling.  This will help ensure that even outside of school hours, kids are getting the healthy diet they need to be their best.  </p><p>Research has shown that since Labor’s School Breakfast Program started, nine out of ten teachers have seen improved student concentration, while six out of ten teachers have noted improved attendance and more than eight out of ten teachers said they now had better relationships with their students. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Minister for Education James Merlino </strong></p><p><em>“The previous government cut Free Fruit Friday, leaving thousands of kids hungry and that tells Victorians everything they need to know about the Liberal’s priorities.”   </em></p><p><em>“If they are given the chance we know they’ll cut school programs again – cuts to breakfast clubs, cuts to the school uniform program and cuts to helping kids go on school camps and excursions.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Member for Northern Victoria Jaclyn Symes  </strong></p><p><em>“We can’t expect kids to concentrate in class on an empty stomach. That’s why we set up free School Breakfast Clubs - and that is why we will expand the program to provide two square meals a day to kids who need it.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Member for Northern Victoria Mark Gepp </strong></p><p><em>“Our School Breakfast Clubs have served up millions of breakfasts to Victorian kids, and teachers are seeing the enormous difference it makes.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for Euroa Fionna Deppeler Morton </strong></p><p><em>“Labor wants to see every child reach their full potential. That’s why we’ll expand this program to the families that need it most.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for Shepparton Bill Heath  </strong></p><p><em>“Sadly there are some kids who come to school without eating and that has a big impact on how they learn. Expanding this program will only help more kids focus in class.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for Ovens Valley Kate Doyle </strong></p><p><em>“The contrast couldn’t be clearer – while the Liberals cut the programs our students need, Labor gets on with expanding them.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-Free-School-Lunches-And-Breakfasts-For-North-East-Students.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">Download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542954554920-K5CZNWQ2VEJFFSZ1FGYJ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Breakfasts-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR NORTH EAST STUDENTS</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR WESTERN VICTORIAN STUDENTS </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:18:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/free-school-lunches-and-breakfasts-for-western-victorian-students</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf79ae1032be49110f0dc21</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>More Western Victorian students will learn on a full stomach with a re-elected Andrews Labor Government to expand the school breakfast program as well as provide free school lunches to 1,000 schools across the state.  </p><p>One in seven kids arrive at school with an empty stomach, making it hard for them to pay attention in class and get the most out of their education. </p><p>That’s why the Andrews Labor Government launched School Breakfast Clubs, which provide 50,000 free breakfasts in 500 Victorian primary schools every week. But there is more to do.  </p><p>More than 217,000 school breakfasts have been delivered across Ballarat over the last four years, while more than 34,000 have been served in the Northern Grampians Shire and more than 33,000 across the Pyrenees Shire. </p><p>A further 42,000 breakfasts have been delivered across Ararat Rural City Council and more than 22,000 across Moorabool Shire.  </p><p>Labor will expand this into a new program that will serve up a free, healthy breakfast and lunch to students in need at 1,000 Victorian Government primary and secondary schools every school day. </p><p>It is estimated that around 10 per cent of children who attend breakfast clubs also come to school with nothing packed for lunch. Often staff will pay for lunch for kids to make sure they have something to eat.  </p><p>The new lunch program will mainly consist of sandwiches, soup, fruit and vegetables. As with the School Breakfast Clubs, Labor will work with Foodbank to include locally sourced food.  </p><p>This expansion is on top of Labor’s recent commitment to establish a new Foodbank Hub in Ballarat. These new food hubs will expand Foodbank’s critical work, extending its fresh food supply to almost 100,000 families and creating new local jobs. </p><p>In contrast, the former Liberal government cut the Education Maintenance Allowance, which went towards supporting local breakfast clubs. All this did was hurt students. Victorians recently saw what could be expected under the Liberals, with the Morrison Government threatening funding cuts for the Foodbank Program.  </p><p>In addition to introducing school lunches, Labor will also provide school holiday backpacks with breakfast supplies to students in need and deliver a series of cooking masterclasses at 100 schools to share nutritional and meal preparation advice and information with families who are struggling.  This will help ensure that even outside school hours, kids are getting the healthy diet they need to be their best.  </p><p>Research has shown that since Labor’s School Breakfast Program started, nine out of ten teachers have seen improved student concentration, while six out of ten teachers have noted improved attendance and more than eight out of ten teachers said they now had better relationships with their students. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Minister for Education James Merlino </strong></p><p><em>“When the Liberals cut Free Fruit Friday, leaving thousands of Victorian kids hungry, it spoke volumes about their agenda.”  </em></p><p><em>“Make no mistake, if they are given the chance they’ll cut school programs again – cuts to breakfast clubs, to the school uniform program and to helping kids go on school camps and excursions.” </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for Wendouree Juliana Addison  </strong></p><p><em>“Having been a teacher for more than a decade, I can tell you a full tummy means better concentration and better outcomes for every student in the classroom.”  </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for Buninyong Michaela Settle  </strong></p><p><em>“As a Breakfast Club volunteer, I’ve seen firsthand how something as simple as a mug of Milo on a cold Ballarat morning can make a big difference to our kids. Only Labor will make sure every child can be their best at school.”   </em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Labor Candidate for Ripon Sarah De Santis </strong></p><p><em>“That the Liberals want to cut school breakfasts and deprive local kids tells you everything you need to know about their priorities.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-Free-School-Lunches-And-Breakfasts-For-Western-Victorian-Students.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">Download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542953853008-TQPDF5N8YDUOODDAZJ5J/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Breakfasts-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">FREE SCHOOL LUNCHES AND BREAKFASTS FOR WESTERN VICTORIAN STUDENTS</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>GIVING OUR KIDS A GOOD MEAL AND A GREAT START IN LIFE </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:14:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/giving-our-kids-a-good-meal-and-a-great-start-in-life</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf798b4aa4a997b55c86bec</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>More Victorian students will be able to learn on a full stomach with a re-elected Andrews Labor Government to expand the school breakfast program as well as providing free school lunches to 1,000 schools.  </p><p>One in seven kids arrive at school with an empty stomach, making it hard for them to pay attention in class and get the most out of their education. </p><p>That’s why the Andrews Labor Government launched School Breakfast Clubs, which currently provides free breakfast to 50,000 kids in 500 Victorian primary schools every week, but there is more to do.  </p><p>Labor will expand this into a new program that will serve up a free, healthy breakfast and lunch to students at 1,000 government primary and secondary schools every day. </p><p>The new lunch program will mainly consist of sandwiches, soup, fruit and vegetables. Similar, to the School Breakfast Clubs, Labor will work with Foodbank to include locally sourced food.  </p><p>In addition to introducing school lunches, Labor will also provide school holiday backpacks with breakfast supplies to students in need and deliver a series of cooking masterclasses at 100 schools to impart nutritional and meal preparation education to disadvantaged families.  This will help make sure that even outside of school, students are getting a more nutritious diet. </p><p>It is estimated that around 10 per cent of children who attend breakfast clubs also come to school with nothing packed for lunch. Often staff will pay for lunch for kids to make sure they have something to eat.  </p><p>Research has shown that since the school breakfast program started, eight out of ten teachers have seen improved student concentration in the classroom, while seven out of ten teachers have noted improved attendance and eight out of ten teachers said they now had better relationships with their students. </p><p>This expansion will make sure that those kids who need it most can get through to home-time on a full stomach. </p><p>In contrast, the former Liberal Government cut the Education Maintenance Allowance, which in some schools was supporting local breakfast clubs. All this did was hurt students. Victorians recently saw what could be expected under the Liberals, with the Morrison Government threatening funding cuts for the Foodbank Program.  </p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Premier Daniel Andrews </strong></p><p><em>“It’s hard to learn when you’re hungry and can’t concentrate in class – that’s why we set up free School Breakfast Clubs and only Labor will expand the program to provide two square meals a day to kids who need it.” </em></p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Minister for Education James Merlino </strong></p><p><em>“The Liberals cut Free Fruit Friday, leaving thousands of Victorian kids hungry and we know they’ll cut school programs again – cuts to breakfast clubs, cuts to the school uniform program and cuts to helping kids go on school camps and excursions.” </em></p><p><em>“School Breakfast Clubs have served up more than six million breakfasts to Victorian students around the state, and teachers are seeing the enormous difference it makes in class.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-Giving-Our-Kids-A-Good-Meal-And-A-Great-Start-In-Life.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542953606068-5VG6SP9MSULKE1G7UNOF/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Breakfasts-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">GIVING OUR KIDS A GOOD MEAL AND A GREAT START IN LIFE</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>NEW FUNDING FOR COMMUNITY INFRASTRUCTURE IN KOROROIT</title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 06:01:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/new-funding-for-community-infrastructure-in-kororoit</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf79757032be49110f0b896</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Member for Kororoit Marlene Kairouz announced today that the Gurdwara Sahib temple in Plumpton will receive $100,000 under a re-elected Andrews Labor Government to upgrade their facilities.</p><p>The announcement follows Labor’s pledge to establish Victoria’s first $3 million Indian Community Infrastructure Fund if re-elected, with all Indian temples and places of worship eligible for funding. </p><p>This will increase access to safe and functional facilities that enable diverse communities in Kororoit to access services participate in activities and share their cultures with the wider community.</p><p>Almost 170,000 Victorians were born in India, making our state home to the largest India-born population in Australia.</p><p>This announcement recognises the contributions of our large Indian communities in Melbourne’s west. </p><p>It builds on Labor’s commitment to invest $14.5 million for land for Indian aged care and $3 million to establish a Bollywood and Indian Cinema Attraction Fund, bringing a minimum of four blockbuster films to our state over the next four years. </p><p>As this announcement shows, only Labor recognises the vast contribution of our proud Indian communities and only Labor is willing to make the investments that really matter.</p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Member for Kororoit Marlene Kairouz </strong></p><p><em>“Labor believes we are stronger for our diversity and is willing to make the investments to back it up.”</em></p><p><em>“Our local Gurdwara told us how important an upgrade to facilities was. We’ve listened.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/NEW-FUNDING-FOR-COMMUNITY-INFRASTRUCTURE-IN-KOROROIT.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">Download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542952851886-559UOI2ZLHOSYOAKJNUJ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Diwali-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">NEW FUNDING FOR COMMUNITY INFRASTRUCTURE IN KOROROIT</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>A BETTER SHRI SHIVA VISHNU TEMPLE FOR CARRUM DOWNS</title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 05:59:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/a-better-shri-shiva-vishnu-temple-for-carrum-downs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf79676aa4a997b55c8535a</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Member for Carrum Sonya Kilkenny has today announced the Shri Shiva Vishnu Temple in Carrum Downs will receive $100,000 to upgrade their facilities, under a re-elected Andrews Labor Government. </p><p>This investment will go towards upgrading the temple’s facilities, enabling diverse communities in Melbourne’s south-east to access services, participate in activities and share their cultures with every Victorian.&nbsp;&nbsp; </p><p>Today’s announcement follows Labor’s pledge to establish Victoria’s first $3 million Indian Community Infrastructure Fund if re-elected, with all Indian temples and places of worship eligible for funding. </p><p>Labor’s commitment also recognises the many contributions of our Indian communities, with almost 170,000 Victorians born in India, making our state home to the largest India-born population in Australia.</p><p>This new investment builds on Labor’s commitment to invest $14.5 million for land for an Indian aged care centre and $3 million to establish a Bollywood and Indian Cinema Attraction Fund. </p><p>Only Labor recognises the vast contribution of our proud Indian communities and only Labor is willing to make the investments that really matter.</p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Minister for Multicultural Affairs Robin Scott</strong></p><p><em>“Labor believes we are stronger and fairer for our diversity—and we are willing to make the investments to back it up.”</em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Member for Carrum Sonya Kilkenny</strong></p><p><em>“For more than 20 years, the Shri Shiva Vishnu Temple has been welcoming thousands of Victorians. We want to support that work and make sure it continues for many years to come.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/A-BETTER-SHRI-SHIVA-VISHNU-TEMPLE-FOR-CARRUM.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">Download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542952738828-7G8X0PZNW5NPE08R5KHQ/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Diwali-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">A BETTER SHRI SHIVA VISHNU TEMPLE FOR CARRUM DOWNS</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>TAKING VICTORIAN STUDENTS TO THE HOME OF DEMOCRACY </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 05:55:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/taking-victorian-students-to-the-home-of-democracy</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf7942f88251b85d9d6eaf2</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Young Victorians will visit Greece to learn more about the home of democracy under a re-elected Andrews Labor Government.</p><p>Labor will establish the Premier’s Spirit of Democracy Prize which will give students the opportunity to win a study tour of Greece every year.</p><p>Greece has contributed so much to the modern world – from philosophy, the Olympics to theatre, science and mathematics, and the origins of modern democracy. This prize will give young Victorians the opportunity to visit where it all started.</p><p>The Prize will be open to all government secondary school students in years 10, 11 and 12. Students will be asked to write about democracy, drawing on the learning of classical Greek thinkers such as Plato and Aristotle. </p><p>Each year, 22 students with the best essays judged by a panel of eminent Victorians, will travel to Greece to learn how the country has shaped politics, culture and thinking across the world. Six of the 22 successful students will be of Greek heritage. </p><p>Funding of $150,000 will go towards the trip each year. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Premier Daniel Andrews</strong></p><p><em>“Education plays a huge role in shaping a person’s future life and this opportunity will give our next generation an appreciation of our democratic heritage.”</em></p><p><em>“The Greeks have given us democracy, mathematics, philosophy and so much more. This is about sharing this history with young Victorians.’</em></p><p><em>“Almost half of all Greek Australians call Melbourne home. This program will help us celebrate the best of ancient Greece with our modern Greek community.”&nbsp; </em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/TAKING-VICTORIAN-STUDENTS-TO-THE-HOME-OF-DEMOCRACY.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">Download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542952460662-SQF44L35JW2RPZH92IWF/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kG5SpE0MsKwe7z-ir8Qvjtd7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QPOohDIaIeljMHgDF5CVlOqpeNLcJ80NK65_fV7S1UfeuwzofiI2qEUaxSckZ5lYhs9lU2Gn8Jq9_d4TmnhxuNigDb9Qy1-VAJiP9oJ1Lyw/22-Andrews+Mikakos+Foley-Gk+Fest270216.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1500" height="998"><media:title type="plain">TAKING VICTORIAN STUDENTS TO THE HOME OF DEMOCRACY</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>30 YEARS OF 3ZZZ MULTICULTURAL RADIO</title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 05:45:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/30-years-of-3zzz-multicultural-radio</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf793ac4fa51a471a4f7edb</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>A re-elected Andrews Labor Government will commit $100,000 over two years to 3ZZZ, the largest ethnic community radio station in Australia. </p><p>The capacity building grant will provide 3ZZZ with the opportunity to expand their services to better involve young people and women from our proud multicultural communities in radio. </p><p>3ZZZ began regular broadcasting in 1989 and now runs more than 60 language programs, supporting Victorians from every background to retain their heritage and language.</p><p>This investment builds on the work of 3ZZZ’s many donors and sponsors, as well as the hard work of its hundreds of volunteers. </p><p>Labor’s commitment will coincide with 3ZZZ’s 30th anniversary in 2019 and recognises the importance of supporting diverse voices in Australia’s media. </p><p>This investment goes to show, only Labor recognises the vast contributions of our multicultural communities, and is willing to make the investments that matter. </p><p>&nbsp;<strong>Quote attributable to Premier Daniel Andrews </strong></p><p><em>&nbsp;“The success of 3ZZZ is a big part of the success of Victorian multiculturalism. This investment is our way of saying thank you.”</em></p><p><em>“This investment will help 3ZZZ expand its important work, heling to share the voices and stories of even more Victorians.”</em></p><p><strong>Quote attributable to Minister for Multicultural Affairs Robin Scott &nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p><p><em>“Labor doesn’t just tolerate diversity and multiculturalism – we embrace and celebrate it.”</em></p>


	<a href="" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" >download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542951948509-RQX67P3OMM2AO5BMQZC6/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Diwali-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">30 YEARS OF 3ZZZ MULTICULTURAL RADIO</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>CELEBRATING OUR MULTICULTURAL FESTIVALS AND COMMUNITIES </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 04:44:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/celebrating-our-multicultural-festivals-and-communities</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf783aab8a045b4c00b9302</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>A re-elected Andrews Labor Government will invest $615,000 in multicultural festivals, events, and celebrations that contribute to our state’s proud diversity, including:</p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p>$80,000 for Wyndham Diwali Mela 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$50,000 towards a Greek festival in Oakleigh 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$10,000 for the Anniversary of the Greek Orthodox Community of Box Hill &amp; Districts 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$5,000 for the Hindu Society of Victoria (Aus) Inc.’s Deepavali 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p></li><li><p>$10,000 for MA Centre (Aust) Pty Ltd.’s Embracing Peace - Grace in Action 2019\</p></li><li><p>$15,000 for Footscray Diwali 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$5,000 for the Melbourne Marathi Mandal’s Diwali Festival 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p> $10,000 for Vivid Diwali – Whittlesea 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$5,000 for Forum for Indian Australians Inc.’s Diwali Lighting Competition 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p></li><li><p>$20,000 for Australian Indian Innovations Inc.’s Diwali 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$80,000 for Wyndham Holi 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$10,000 for the Launch of Thoolika: Malayalam Annual Literary Publication from Melbourne</p></li><li><p>$100,000 for the Hispanic Latin American Festival 2019&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$5,000 for the Macedonian Food Festival 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$30,000 for the Peel Street Festival 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$50,000 over two years for the Polish Festival @ Federation Square&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$70,000 for Vaisakhi at Federation Square 2019&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$50,000 for Casey Garba Festival 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$10,000 for Anatolian Alevi Festival 2019&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li></ul><p>Labor’s commitment to celebrating our state’s proud diversity will extend to supporting multicultural and multi-faith organisations. </p><p>A re-elected Labor Government will provide $1.93 million to over 50 multicultural and multi-faith organisations for initiatives that strengthen participation, inclusion, or family violence services.</p><p>Labor will also provide $2.1 million for multicultural infrastructure projects that support communities to preserve and share their culture and traditions in a space that they can make their own, including:</p><ul data-rte-list="default"><li><p>$40,000 for upgrades and renovations at the Greek Orthodox Parish of St. Raphael in Bentleigh</p></li><li><p>$20,000 for upgrades and renovations at the Holy Monastary of Axion Estin in Northcote &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$20,000 for upgrades and renovations at the Chios Brotherhood Korais of Melbourne and Victoria in Reservoir &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$80,000 for upgrades and renovations at St Anargiri Orthodox Church in Oakleigh&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li><li><p>$100,000 to the Sikh Community of Greater Geelong Inc. as seed funding for a new temple </p></li><li><p>$80,000 for upgrades and renovations at the Craigieburn Sikh Gurdwara </p></li><li><p>$40,000 for upgrades and renovations at the Australia Western Thrace Turkish Association of Victoria’s community centre; </p></li><li><p>An additional $1.9 million to help make the Vietnamese Cultural Centre and Museum a reality&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p></li></ul><p>&nbsp;Labor will strengthen Victoria’s community media sector by providing $500,000 for a dedicated grants program for multicultural media organisations across the state. &nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;And reflected the importance of supporting a diverse media, Labor will update the Victorian Government’s advertising guidelines to maintain the multicultural media spend at 5 per cent but no longer include SBS TV in the calculation. Labor will also update the Victorian Government’s advertising guidelines to maintain the regional media spend at 15 per cent but remove regional TV from the calculation.</p><p>&nbsp;<strong>Quotes attributable to Minister for Multicultural Affairs Robin Scott &nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p><p><em>“Labor doesn’t just tolerate diversity and multiculturalism – we embrace and celebrate it.”</em></p><p><em>“Labor invests in our multicultural communities because we know that our multiculturalism make us stronger, fairer, and a place we can all be proud of.”</em></p>


	<a href="" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" >DOWNLOAD THE MEDIA RELEASE</a>

<p><em>&nbsp;</em></p>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542948241421-DJJP1WT9OMQXTJREFBAD/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/Diwali-010.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">CELEBRATING OUR MULTICULTURAL FESTIVALS AND COMMUNITIES</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>MORE MAJOR ARTWORKS TO BOOST TOURISM AND SUPPORT JOBS </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 04:31:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/more-major-artworks-to-boost-tourism-and-support-jobs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf781cf6d2a73887b66f723</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>More silo art and large-scale murals will pop up around Melbourne and regional Victoria under a re-elected Andrews Labor Government – revitalising communities, boosting tourism and supporting local jobs. </p><p>Victoria’s reputation as the Creative State is built on our world-class galleries, vibrant live music and theatre scene, and the breathtaking art trails that have sprung up across regional Victoria. </p><p>Through these large-scale art installations, old industrial buildings and silos across the state have been brought back to life, with art work that acknowledges the history and people of the region.  </p><p>They have also brought huge economic benefits to regional Victoria, attracting visitors and tourism dollars to small towns throughout the state. </p><p>And it’s not just the regions that have reaped the benefits of major art projects. The twenty-storey mural recently unveiled on the public housing estate in Collingwood has helped re-energise the area and honour the people who call the flats home. </p><p>We want to bring these benefits to more of Victoria – that’s why a re-elected Labor Government will provide an additional $1 million for more silo art and murals on buildings across Victoria. </p><p>Artists from across Victoria, Australia and the world will have the opportunity to apply for grants of up to $300,000 to transform more buildings into art. </p><p>Local and regional councils will also be able to apply for grants for viewing platforms, toilets and picnic facilities near the art works, ensuring visitors have the best possible experience while they’re there. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Minister for Creative Industries Martin Foley </strong></p><p><em>“Art can revitalise a region, honour its history and change its future – that’s why we investing in more art installations across Victoria.” </em></p><p><em>“The Silo Art Trail has been a game changer for the Wimmera Mallee region – increasing tourism, boosting business and supporting local jobs. We want to bring those benefits to more suburbs and towns across the state.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-More-Major-Artworks-To-Boost-Tourism-And-Support-Jobs.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">Download the media release</a>

<p><em>﻿</em><br></p>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542947483729-USFQ2TYHZIJOHYXCLMEI/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kPJXHKy2-mnvrsdpGQjlhod7gQa3H78H3Y0txjaiv_0fDoOvxcdMmMKkDsyUqMSsMWxHk725yiiHCCLfrh8O1z5QHyNOqBUUEtDDsRWrJLTmihaE5rlzFBImxTetd_yW5btdZx37rH5fuWDtePBPDaHF5LxdCVHkNEqSYPsUQCdT/art.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="1000" height="1000"><media:title type="plain">MORE MAJOR ARTWORKS TO BOOST TOURISM AND SUPPORT JOBS</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>ANDREW KATOS AND THE LIBERALS ABANDON SOUTH BARWON ALREADY </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 04:09:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/andrew-katos-and-the-liberals-abandon-south-barwon-already</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf745fe4fa51a471a4c33c7</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Matthew Guy has today confirmed they will cut services, privatise assets, sack workers and stop building the infrastructure South Barwon needs. </p><p>They have revealed a massive $39 billion budget black hole and secret plans to cut services and sack workers on the eve of the state election. </p><p>The Liberals costings have revealed they have short-changed the Barwon community $220 million for the Barwon Heads Road duplication, only committing $70 million of the $290 million they promised.  </p><p>Andrew Katos appears to have forgotten the Torquay Aquatic and Leisure Centre altogether.  </p><p>Labor will fund the Barwon Heads Road Duplication to get locals where they need to go safer and sooner.   </p><p>Only Labor can also deliver a brand new Torquay Aquatic and Leisure Centre to ensure local families have the facilities they deserve, close to home.  </p><p>Labor will keep standing up against Liberal cuts and closures – and continue our record as a government for hardworking families, not corporations. </p><p>Only Labor has a fully-costed, fully-funded plan that delivers for all Victorians. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Treasurer Tim Pallas </strong></p><p><em>“The proof is now on paper – Matthew Guy will sack workers and cut services that Victorians rely on to pay for his promises.” </em></p><p><em>“Only Labor has a fully-costed, fully-funded plan that delivers for all Victorians.” </em></p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Labor Candidate for South Barwon Darren Cheeseman </strong></p><p><em>“We all know the legacy of the Liberals is one of cuts and closures.” </em></p><p><em>“Only Labor can be trusted to deliver the much needed Barwon Heads Road duplication and provide locals with the new facilities they deserve through a brand new Torquay Aquatic and Leisure Centre.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-Andrew-Katos-And-The-Liberals-Abandon-South-Barwon-Already.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">Download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542946159343-7EPWSRJQP6LQPHWVJA44/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kFQQgP34qnCpeHaeAOzTt7pZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PICHnXC1b9smDvYLPdL-DS7U1pkhCtl83kemXd5r3C5ngKMshLAGzx4R3EDFOm1kBS/hands.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="800" height="800"><media:title type="plain">ANDREW KATOS AND THE LIBERALS ABANDON SOUTH BARWON ALREADY</media:title></media:content></item><item><title>LOUISE STALEY AND THE LIBERALS SHORT CHANGE RIPON </title><dc:creator>Imam Andrews</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:11:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://www.danandrews.com.au/policies/louise-staley-and-the-liberals-short-change-ripon</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93:5b99e4554d7a9ce10e153777:5bf745156d2a73887b646d13</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The Victorian Liberals and Nationals has now confirmed they will cut services, privatise assets, sack workers and stop building the infrastructure Ripon needs. </p><p>They have revealed a massive $39 billion budget black hole and secret plans to cut services and sack workers on the eve of the state election. </p><p>For Ripon, in a mad rush to get in front of the camera, Louise Staley committed $100 million to transform Maryborough Hospital, however yesterday’s costings have revealed only $40 million has been allocated towards this much needed upgrade. </p><p>Not only has the Coalition has failed to match Labor’s commitment to build a community sports hub for Miners Rest, they’ve short-changed this important community project $4 million.  </p><p>A re-elected Labor Government will invest $100 million to rebuild Maryborough Hospital, which will include acute medical and surgery beds, another operating theatre and more consultation rooms. </p><p>Labor also understands the importance of a world-class education and will build a new school at Miners Rest, with a community sports hub for the whole community through a $21.6 million commitment.  </p><p>Labor will keep standing up against Liberal cuts and closures – and continue our record as a government for hardworking families, not corporations. </p><p>Only Labor has a fully-costed, fully-funded plan that delivers for all Victorians. </p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Treasurer Tim Pallas </strong></p><p><em>“The proof is now on paper – Matthew Guy will sack workers and cut services that Victorians rely on to pay for his promises.” </em></p><p><em>“Only Labor has a fully-costed, fully-funded plan that delivers for all Victorians.” </em></p><p><strong>Quotes attributable to Candidate for Ripon Sarah De Santis </strong></p><p><em>“We all know the legacy of Liberal National Governments is one of cuts and closures.” </em></p><p><em>“Labor will transform Maryborough Hospital, build a new school at Miners Rest and deliver the services that locals need.”</em></p>


	<a href="https://www.danandrews.com.au/s/181123-Louise-Staley-And-The-Liberals-Short-Change-Ripon.pdf" class="sqs-block-button-element--small sqs-block-button-element" target="_blank">Download the media release</a>]]></description><media:content type="image/jpeg" url="https://images.squarespace-cdn.com/content/v1/5b46af5a55b02cea2a648e93/1542931856479-Q5EW08BPNQD3I4R5ZPHW/ke17ZwdGBToddI8pDm48kFQQgP34qnCpeHaeAOzTt7pZw-zPPgdn4jUwVcJE1ZvWQUxwkmyExglNqGp0IvTJZamWLI2zvYWH8K3-s_4yszcp2ryTI0HqTOaaUohrI8PICHnXC1b9smDvYLPdL-DS7U1pkhCtl83kemXd5r3C5ngKMshLAGzx4R3EDFOm1kBS/hands.jpg?format=1500w" medium="image" isDefault="true" width="800" height="800"><media:title type="plain">LOUISE STALEY AND THE LIBERALS SHORT CHANGE RIPON</media:title></media:content></item></channel></rss>