Last year, the Government announced a
$100 million upgrade to Flinders Street Station.
That's partly because it's a great
icon of Melbourne and Victoria,
but it's also a really important part
of our public transport network.
It's a station that has more than 26 million
passenger trips through it every single year.
It's a busy station, it's a grand station,
and we're wanting to restore its facade in particular.
Our role in the Flinders Street Station project has
been to survey and assess the condition of the building,
and in particular to investigate the original
decoration or paint treatment to the building.
We were able to establish from newspaper
accounts that it's been painted at least 5 times
since it was originally painted
around the early 1910s, 1915 period.
To assist with the analysis, we employed the
Grimwade Centre for Cultural Materials Conservation,
which is based at Melbourne University.
Their role was primarily to sort out what the
inorganic material was in the paint systems,
so that would assist us in
establishing what the colours were.
We started by first taking many, many samples
from a representative component of the building.
We then embed those samples in the polyester resin.
And then we slice the resin so we can actually see
all the layers, so it's like looking at this wonderful
multilayered liquorice allsort.
The next stage was to take the samples to
earth sciences at the University of Melbourne.
And we have equipment there
called a scanning electron microscope.
It's very high resolution, very high magnification.
We're able to do an inorganic analysis of the
pigment particles, so that gives us further information
about what colour we're dealing with over the years.
What was really interesting is that the analysis
showed us that all of the paints were, in a sense,
commercial paints that you would expect
of the period when the building was repainted.
So the building, while shades have varied, has been typically repainted consistently in stone colours
to the render and dark greens to the woodwork.
Before state registered buildings, the preference
is that the color schemes be investigated,
and if the original colour scheme is important or important to the architecture of the building,
typically their preference is that it
be repainted in the original scheme.
I'm really pleased to announce that part
of this restoration of Flinders Street Station
involves the repainting of the facade,
and that is going to be done in the original 1910 colours that Flinders Street Station was originally painted in.