This year’s Budget is focused on building
on the new found strength of the Victorian
economy to deliver the things that matter
most to Victorians: hospitals, schools, jobs
and transport to protect our quality of life.
The Budget funds our plans, projects and promises
because getting things done means concrete
delivery, not dithering and delay.
We’re building the projects our state needs
and creating thousands of jobs.
We’re supporting businesses to grow and
making sure Victorians get the skills they
need.
The Budget sets aside $500 million to take
action family violence – our number one
law and order issue.
It will deliver more new schools than ever
before.
It will cut waiting times for emergency departments
and elective surgeries.
It funds the road and rail projects we need
to get to work and home on time.
And it recognises regional Victoria as key
to our state’s economic strength.
With this Budget, regional cities can start
to rival Melbourne in the race for new jobs,
visitors and businesses – and that’s a
good thing.
Make no mistake: our economy is strong.
Companies who want to invest in Victoria and
create new jobs now know they have a government
that’s on their side and the Victorian economy
has a new-found confidence.
They are just some of the reasons why our
state is growing faster than any other.
It’s our job to manage this growth, and
make sure no Victorian misses out on the things
that really matter.
It will take time and effort, but I’m proud
to say that we’re getting it done.