After a 12 month international competitive
tender process, I am very pleased that these
High Capacity Metro Trains, 65 trains, $2
billion worth of work. That work has been
won by the consortium led by Downer and that
work will be undertaken in this workshop right
here.
Those 65 trains are an extra carriage long,
they have a 20% increase in the overall capacity,
what does that mean? Well on the Cranbourne
Pakenham line, where they'll run from the
beginning of 2019, we will see 39,000 extra
passengers able to travel on that, our busiest
line.
These are the trains that will service the
Metro Tunnel when we connect the Dandenong
line with the Sunbury line. They'll have the
latest technology, the latest design, there
will be better information for passengers
within the trains themselves, contributing
overall to a better public transport experience.
So we're not just getting new trains, made
proudly in Victoria by Victorians, we're also
breathing new life into the rolling stock
industry here in this state.
The overall job number on this contract is
1,100 jobs. 15% of those jobs will be apprentices,
trainees or cadet engineers. This is all good,
strong news.
Trains for Victorians built by Victorians.