Last year, we took a positive plan
to the people of Victoria.
With this year's Budget, we're delivering
on that plan, and delivering on our promises.
Before we came to government,
we promised to remove 50 of our most dangerous
and congested levels crossing by 2022.
With 29 crossings already gone for good,
now we’re getting on with removing even more –
investing $6.6 billion dollars to remove
a total of 75 level crossings by 2025.
Getting Victorians out of traffic and home sooner.
We’re delivering the Suburban Transport Blitz –
transforming suburban rail, upgrading suburban
roads, and fully funding North East Link.
Just like we said we would.
We’re investing in regional Victoria too –
fixing regional roads, building more regional trains,
and doing it using local workers and local materials.
From fixing the roundabout at the end of your street
to building our state’s biggest transport projects,
this Budget will get you where you need to go.
We also promised to put power back in the
hands of Victorians,
and by installing solar on more than 700,000 homes, that’s exactly what we’re doing.
We’re building and fixing our hospitals,
and investing in healthy smiles for our kids,
with the rollout of free dental
for students across the state.
And because Victorians deserve
quality care wherever they live,
we’re delivering 500,000 extra appointments for
medical specialists for patients in regional Victoria.
Bringing your baby home for the first time is
one of the most precious and daunting moments
for any parent.
With this Budget, we’re making sure new
parents have the support they need.
with new parenting centres and new baby
bundles for our youngest Victorians.
We’re making sure those same young Victorians
get the very best start in life –
building better classrooms,
17 brand-new schools,
and rolling out three-year-old kinder
for every Victorian child.
These are the things we said we would do.
And with this Budget, we’re keeping our promises
and delivering for all Victorians.