today I'm very pleased to announce I'm
proud to announce that we will invest
significantly to remove 9 level
crossings all the level crossings
between Caulfield and Daniel on will go
they'll be put out to the market as one
package of works those 9 level crossings
will go that that work will be finished
by the end of 2018 will order 37
high-capacity trains this is the very
best of new technology to make sure that
we can move more passengers and get them
to their destination faster these trains
will be made locally a minimum 50% local
content target on build and of course
maintenance will be done locally there's
a Depot to be built out it's a Pakenham
there are power upgrades and
conventional signalling upgrades on this
pocket and Cranbourne line and there is
also very importantly a proper trial of
high capacity signalling on the
Sandringham line not trialing new
technology on our busiest rail line the
packet and Cranbourne line but instead
doing a discreet trial the way it should
be done on the Sandringham line so this
is good for safety it's good for traffic
congestion it's good for jobs and it's
good for public transport users in
Melbourne busiest and public transport
corridor I'm very very proud to be able
to commit our government to this
significant package of works this will
be many billions of dollars it will
secure jobs improve services improve
safety as well it's exactly what we said
it would do and we're proud to be able
to pin it to it today we're taking a
pathway that's about putting passengers
first putting in place a program of
works that's designed to address
congestion to increase capacity by
around 42 percent by purchasing 37
high-capacity trains longer trains that
can carry more passengers on the extra
services that will be delivered along
this line this is the careful planning
work that's gone into
delivering this program of works that's
needed it's a better approach it's a
bigger approach but most importantly
it's an approach that puts whether
you're a public transport passenger or a
motorist sitting in a car in the in the
south eastern suburbs of Melbourne this
will be a program that will see you get
to get to work quicker and get home
earlier to the family at the end of the
day through the program of removing
level crossings and the delivery of F
trains it's the right project for this
set for this line and it's a program
that with the premiere we are very keen
to get cracking on implementing over the
next step over the next three years
Not authorised by the Victorian Government 1
Treasury place Melbourne