The Victorian Government will build the North East Link,
finally completing the missing
link in Melbourne’s road network.
After almost 50 years of disconnected freeways,
the North East Link will connect the M80 Ring Road
to the Eastern Freeway and EastLink.
Expected to carry more than 100,000 vehicles a day,
the project will connect the millions of people
living in Melbourne’s north, east and south-east
to jobs, schools and hospitals,
slash travel times and congestion
in Melbourne’s northern suburbs,
take trucks off local roads, with better
access between key industrial centres
and a connection from the east to the airport,
create thousands of jobs during construction,
and protect our suburbs and the
environment with advanced tunneling.
Planning and consultation will start in 2017,
with a chance for Victorians to have their say
on the best way to get this project done.