we're going to get some lunch I need you
to stay here I'll be very quick okay
I'm gonna be very quick how many times
have you opted for the easy option like
leaving the kids in the car while you
quickly run into the shops and I bet you
never thought you're actually putting
your kids lives in danger by doing so
within minutes the temperature inside a
parked car can be twice as hot as the
outside my boys body temperature rises
three to five times faster than mine and
guess what leaving the window down has
very little effect on the inside okay
boys I need you to be quick we've got to
go into the shops leaving your kids in
the car is dangerous at any time of the
year but it can be catastrophic over
summer our valuables should never be
left in the car
[Music]
you