Building a station in a major city is like
open heart surgery. You've got to keep the
body moving, the city moving, the blood pumping.
We can't just stop everything dead, so we're
keeping the city moving as much as possible.
To manage traffic disruptions during construction,
we'll be working with VicRoads and the City
of Melbourne on diversion strategies to get
people around to where they want to go. Obviously
on a project of this scale, there's some potential
for short-term closures from time to time.
La Trobe Street, Collins Street, Bourke Street
trams will continue to operate as they do
today, and at Flinders Street, there will
need to be some closures. There will be some
disruptions on the likes of Flinders Street,
There will be some disruptions
on the likes of Flinders Street,
where we're connecting the CBD South Station
to Flinders Street Station. We'll be occupying
City Square for a number of years. Those are
sort of the disruptions that we'll be seeing
at CBD South. At CBD North, there'll be a
lot of work happening within Franklin Street.
Alternatives will be put in place to make
sure people can still get around the city
as they do today.