I begin by acknowledging the traditional
owners of the land on which we meet and
pay my respects to their elders past and
present
delegates I say it and I mean it because
I'm not acknowledging a lifestyle choice
I'm acknowledging the oldest continuous
culture known to human history can we
think our deputy leader our deputy
premier for his words today and he's
work in making Victoria the education
state in the room today of course can we
also welcome party president Rupert
Evans and state secretary Noah Carol
fresh off a win Noah was the campaign
director but he knows we couldn't have
done it without the members of our
campaign team the members of our
Community Action Network to everyone who
filled a shift work the phones knocked
on doors and stood on street corners to
every man and woman young and old who
gave their time and their toil to a
cause that's greater than us all our
party says thank you and I say thank you
so every nurse every firefighter and
every paramedic teacher and tradie who
joined us - every candidate every
delegate every colleague every member of
our movement every member of a union I
was proud to stand by your side
delegates I said on election night that
some wanted an election all about unions
all about workers and their families and
that's exactly what they got during that
campaign we rallied with the people
who'd been left behind we stood up for
the families who were failed we spoke to
the kids who wanted a skill who wanted a
job who wanted to build a better life
for themselves with their own hands we
put people first and they gave us a
great responsibility the right to form a
strong and stable majority labor
government the people of Victoria didn't
just change the government they started
something that will change our state
they asked for better schools and
stronger tapes to give their kids a
chance they asked for more trains and
fewer level crossings to get home safer
and sooner they asked for a health
system that cares for them and the
people they love and today I can tell
you we are getting on with it one of the
proudest moments of my professional life
came on the first day of our labor
government I was down at some Vincent's
Hospital with a dozen or so paramedics
like our fire five
and nurses paramedics carry a weight
that most of us could not but there was
a time not too long ago when their own
government their own employer abused
them attacked them and betrayed them
paramedics and their patients lives were
lost and it simply had to stop that's
why on the first day of our government I
stood side-by-side with those women and
men and proudly declared war is over
today delegates we're working with
paramedics not against them to save the
minutes that save lives and we've begun
the hard work to recruit additional
firefighters to equip them to protect
them because after all they protect us
and the dangerous and perhaps deadly
fisk ville training center it has closed
for good today
Victoria's nurses and midwives have for
the first time in four years a
government that respects their work
today the emergency funds are flowing
into our TAFE system bringing our
campuses back from the brink helping
them survive and helping them to thrive
and today we're harnessing the power of
the government's purchase to secure
local jobs and local skills because
we're focused on employment growth right
here in Victoria not on the other side
of the world
friends were getting our state back to
work we're getting our transport system
back on track medical cannabis is one
step closer adoption equality is one
step closer water is flowing into Lake
to londo and cattle out of the high
country northern Metrorail will be part
of our future and deadly level crossings
will be part of our past
delegates at our last state conference I
gave the most important speech I've ever
given I announced our plan to establish
Australia's first Royal Commission into
the country's number one law and order
crisis Family Violence our national
emergency and today I can inform you
that that Royal Commission is fully
underway it will give us the answers we
need because I know that more of the
same policy will mean more of the same
tragedy we have led the way we will make
the change and that will save lives
the Royal Commission came from speaking
with thousands of Victorians those comp
those conversations convinced me that we
had to act but they also convinced me
that outcomes for women start with
attitudes toward women and that's what I
want to talk to you about today let me
tell you about some of the public
institutions that help our state get
things done hospitals the guardians of
our health courts the guardians of our
justice system types and universities
the guardians of our future from the
Commission's and agencies and services
that review reform and make sure no one
misses out to the galleries and museums
that make us the cultural capital of
Australia these are the organisations
that dictate the day-to-day lives of
every Victorian their success determines
ours as a state their performance
determines ours as a people so it
concerns me it really does when they
aren't as good as they can be when they
aren't representative of the people they
serve it concerns me when their
leadership doesn't reflect contemporary
Victoria many of the boardrooms of our
public bodies are lacking a balance of
skills a balance of views
a balance of experiences a balance of
knowledge because they're lacking
perhaps the most important balance of
all delegates they're lacking women
now a lot of people in this room made a
lot of noise when Tony Abbot found only
one seat that his cabinet table to
represent more than 11 million
Australian women but but we're fooling
ourselves if we think the problem starts
and ends there our cabinet is very
different and I'm very proud of that
but understand this when it comes to
women on major government boards the
federal government performs better than
Victoria and I'm not very proud of that
at all and it's even worse because we're
going backwards female representation on
major government boards in Victoria has
fallen from 40 percent to a little over
35 percent in just four years
delegates consider these facts in
Victoria women make up 80 percent of the
workforce in the health and social care
sector but the proportion of women on
the board of Melbourne health less than
a quarter women make up 69 percent of
the workforce in education and training
but the proportion of women on the
council at RMIT and Victoria University
less than a third more Victorian women
are graduating from university than men
here in the ideas capital but Melbourne
University proportionally it has fewer
female council members than any other
university in Australia and it doesn't
it doesn't in there public transport
Victoria less than a fifth of its board
are women Treasury Corporation less than
a quarter the country fire authority
less than a quarter the supreme and
county courts less than a third of our
judges are women but all of this it
isn't their fault it is indeed our fault
government appointments after all are
made by the government now we do have it
an intention an aspiration a
well-meaning goal for better
representation on all government boards
it was implemented some six years ago
and yet we're going backwards and I say
this morning I am tired of targets like
these becoming an increasingly eloquent
measure of our failure it's time to turn
that target into something tangible it
is something real that's why I can
announce today delegates but from now on
under our labor government no less than
50% of all future appointments to all
paid government boards and all Victorian
courts will be women
it is not it is not a target it is not
an aspiration
it's an assurance of all the
appointments that my government makes
between now and November 2018 including
all judges and magistrates at least one
half of them will be women and I will be
accountable for that delegates this is a
step forward for our state public
institutions that actually represent the
public that means balance it means
better decisions that means reaching
deeper into a growing pool of talent
training more people from different
backgrounds to become leaders of our
state now we talked about the lack of
women on corporate boards well this is
the first step to fix it I'm not going
to tell companies how to run their
affairs but I do have something to say
about this attitude that there aren't
enough qualified women going around I
don't agree with that I simply don't but
even if you accept that argument isn't
it time that we did something about it
what I've announced today will mean that
by the end of 2018
no director of an asx200 company will be
able to look me in the eye and tell me
that there aren't enough women in our
state who are qualified to sit around
their boardroom tables
delegates this is no token gesture it's
very real because I am sick and tired of
attending big meetings where the only
people there are blokes how does that
help the progress of our states how does
that guarantee the best decisions how
does that influence the culture of an
organization for the better the fact is
when organizations lose diversity they
lose touch and eventually we all lose
out because bad attitudes produce bad
results not just in organizations but in
our society some are obvious some are
hidden some are destructive all of them
need to be challenged that's why I want
to make it very clear to you today that
under this Labour government equality is
not negotiable
delegates last year's election was not
simply about defeating our opponents it
was all about winning the right to
govern to reform rebuild and reshape our
state to make sure that every Victorian
can reach their full potential because
only then will we all reach ours
Victorians voted for a positive plan and
the team with the energy to deliver it
they voted for better schools and better
hospitals better public transport they
voted for skills for jobs for action on
family violence they voted to put people
first and friends make no mistake we are
getting on with it thank you very much
you