The Victorian Government is delivering the $440 million Murray Basin Rail Project.
Standardising the Murray Basin's rail network
provides industry with better access to the national rail network,
enabling movement of goods such as grain,
mineral sands,
and fresh produce to neighbouring states and to international markets.
The Murray Basin Rail Project will allow
an extra 500,000 tonnes of grain,
and 450,000 tonnes of general freight,
including wine, food and nuts,
to be transported by rail per year.
It will remove an estimated 20,000 truck trips from our roads every year,
create almost 300 construction jobs,
and provide regional economic opportunities,
including the production of concrete sleepers, which will
support more than 20 jobs at Austrak in Geelong.
To find out more, visit ptv.vic.gov.au.