NADINE: We're building a rail tunnel. It will have
five stations and about 9 kilometres of rail tunnel.
PAUL: The reason for the tunneling is mainly
because we are in a quite a heavily urbanised
area and tunneling avoids disruption to the
roads and the surface infrastructure. A TPM
– or a tunnel boring machine – is designed
to respond to the geotechnical conditions
that are below the ground for the tunneling,
whether it's rock, whether it's soil, what
the groundwater conditions are, where the
groundwater table is, is the rock very hard,
is the ground very soft.
Typically, there
are two ways of launching a tunnel boring
machine – either through a portal or through
a shaft. For this project, we're planning
to use shafts and so you excavate a large
shaft, and then you lower the TBM in segments
and assemble it underground to form the full
machine.