rooftop solar for 650,000 Victorian
homes that's what we will deliver
there's no denying making ends meet is
getting harder they told us that
privatization would make power cheaper
but ever since then prices keep going up
while big energy companies make record
profits labour will put the power back
in your hands or put solar panels on six
hundred and fifty thousand Victorian
homes you will pay nothing up front
we'll give you half the costs for free
and the rest you can pay back over for
four years interest-free it'll save you
up to $900 a year on your bills
real money back in your pocket but the
pockets of big energy companies CEOs
we've been building renewable energy to
make power cheaper now we'll bring it to
your home but only under a reelected
Labour
[Music]
[Applause]