This is a massive project. It's the largest
rail shut down — which we'll be undertaking
in the next few weeks — since the construction
of the Melbourne underground rail network
back in the '80s, so we're very excited about
that. In the 37 days, we'll be excavating
out to lower the rail line to 7 metres deep
below its existing level. We'll be digging
out about 260,000 m³ of excavated material
and taking it away from the site in trucks,
so expect to see a lot of trucks on the road
for that period. We're working 24/7 with up
to 1000 people onsite in a shift. We understand
that's going to be quite disruptive for the
community and traders. We'll be building the
new railway line and starting to build the
three new stations. And at the end of the
37 days, we'll be opening the first station
here at McKinnon Road.
North Road, McKinnon Road
and Centre Road traders, they're still
open for business during the major construction
works and the road closures that are involved.
There will be increased traffic with trucks,
but there is still plenty of parking available
for customers during that time.
We've got lots of workers with their parking so making sure that we're not blocking the residents from being
able to access their homes and keeping everything safe.
We make a bit of mess on
the road. Straight away, we get the sweepers
over, clean it up, try to make as little as
possible damage to them.
It will be noisy.
Understand that it's going to be disruptive
and ask that people just come to us with any
concerns they've got and we'll do our best
to respond.
Our community relations team will be on call 24 hours during the out of hours works and they'll be able to
reach our team directly during that time.
It'll make life so much easier
for cars and pedestrians and people
that live nearby. And we'll put up with the
mess at the moment because it'll be good.
It is a bit of short-term pain and it's a
really big long-term gain so let's just keep
the long term in mind.