The decision was then "Where?"
We looked at the various options that were available to us.
We thought about where we're going to have the biggest talent pool.
Where's the real fashion centre within Australia?
Where's the retail centre within Australia?
Where's the right infrastructure for us?
Where's the best proximity to our distribution network within Australia?
And the answer to all of those was Melbourne.
It is a great city. It is known as the fashion and retail centre.
We've had a long relationship with Melbourne.
We know what it's like to work in Victoria and we like it.
It's surprising how much growth there is, you know, in economic terms.
Mildura is still in growth mode.
Health and education, they're our strongest employers.
Although we also have agriculture, manufacturing, engineering –
you know, there are some quite healthy areas as far as employment goes.
I think it is a surprise to people just how vibrant the communities are.
It was a natural place for us to open.
We had a lot of excitement, a lot of great customers in the region,
and we could hire a lot of great talent here.
We've been blessed with hiring a great, great team of engineers and data scientists here.
We resolved to build our own state-of-the-art facility right here as you see it today.
We will train the next generation of highly valued
expert technicians right here in this facility.
And we have partnered with Kangan Institute and their Automotive Centre of Excellence
to deliver an end-to-end training program for our apprentice technicians.