there's no doubt at all this is an
iconic building it's a great space in
the center of our city it is a fantastic
precinct but one that needs to be so
much better this is a grand old building
that has been allowed to really crumble
and we have to do much better than that
that's why I'm so very proud today to
announce that our government will invest
a hundred million dollars to both
complete heritage works to bring this
grand old building back to its former
glory back to the iconic status that we
know it needs to enjoy but also a very
significant investment in making sure
that the two hundred thousand Victorians
who use this station this precinct every
single day have a much better public
transport experience it's about the
basics it's about focusing on things
that make such a big difference
signage the surfacing the finish of the
platforms the ability to find your way
around the station the ability to use
toilets that are of an appropriate
standard they're just not at the moment
the roof leaks we've got water damage
right throughout the whole building we
need to make these investments to make
sure that this is a better facility a
better experience for public transport
users but also to return this grand old
building this icon so its former glory
around 105 years ago this building
opened as the most modern piece of
architecture of its time as a fully
functioning railway station for the city
of Melbourne we are so fortunate more
than a century later to continue to have
such a wonderful asset for our city
still being used for the purpose it was
designed for as a fully functioning
transport hub a hub for our rail network
here into Melbourne and across the
suburbs there is a lot of work to be
done to bring back some of the former
glory of this of this building we also
recognize that this is a facility that's
very much fit for purpose as a public
transport hub and that's why significant
amount of this funding is going to be
invested in improving the passenger
experience improving the lighting
particularly in the in the underneath
passageways and improving the
information that is provided to
passengers and we're very pleased to be
able to breathe new life and a new
beginning into Flinders Street Station
you