The Victorian Government is upgrading and widening the Monash Freeway to get you home safer and sooner.
The project is upgrading 44
kilometres of the Monash Freeway
between Chadstone and Pakenham.
During the construction of extra lanes,
your commute will change with 30 kilometres of
barriers in place to keep drivers and workers safe.
The same number of lanes will
remain open during the peak,
and construction will be staged
to avoid major disruption.
Plan your trip ahead and leave
a little more time just in case.
We'll have you moving sooner
with works finishing in 2018.
By upgrading the Monash and
building the Western Distributor Tunnel,
we'll reduce congestion, and improve safety and reliability from Geelong to Pakenham.
Stay in touch with the Monash Freeway upgrade to find out about changes that may affect you.