hi I'm Dan Andrews it's been a busy year
for me as it's been for so many
Victorians I'm really looking forward to
spending some time with the people that
I love the people that are so special to
me in my life my wife Katherine our kids
now are Grace and Joe that's what the
holiday season is all about it's also
about being thankful for the blessings
you have and being generous with the
things you give to others behind me is a
Kmart Wishing Tree
since came-up began the appeal more than
25 years ago they've collected more than
6 million gifts for needy families for
kids who need that special helping hand
at Christmastime I hope that we've all
done our bit in the Victorian Government
in the Premier's office to keep these
presents coming I know they're going to
go to kids who really need them so my
message to Victorian families is very
simple really
enjoy this special time with family and
friends take time to reflect on all that
you've achieved this year and all those
things in your life and the life of
those you love which is so special take
time also to think about those
Victorians who do it tough over this
summer period over this Christmas and
New Year period be safe on our roads be
careful have fun of course enjoy all
that our state has to offer again a very
Merry Christmas a safe prosperous new
year
one of hardwork and real achievement
making our great state fairer and
stronger for the future