Daniel Andrews has been a special guest at
Memorial Day in New York, honouring America's
fallen soldiers. He's also spoken out in support
of Chief Commissioner Graham Ashton over a
crackdown on violent masked thugs.
Brendan Donohoe is travelling with the Premier.
The Premier started the day with vegemite on toast
at the Australian-owned Bluestone Cafe before
joining the front row VIPs at the annual Memorial
Day commemoration.
It's a federal holiday
and the most sombre as it remembers the 1.2
million American men and women killed in armed
conflicts, including World Wars I and II,
Korea, Vietnam, the Middle East and Afghanistan.
US Navy chief Admiral John Richardson and
New York Mayor Bill de Blasio appreciated
the support from down under, with the Premier
invited to lay a wreath in the memory of Allied
soldiers killed fighting along with the United States.
It's a great honour to be here today
to remember those who have fallen in the defence
of our freedom, for our whole world.
On home-grown law and order issues,
the Premier announced he supports the Chief Commissioner, Graham Ashton,
and new laws to ban violent thugs
wearing masks at public protests and other events.
The powers necessary, the resources
necessary, that's how we'll fight crime and
keep our Victorian community safe.
The Premier says any changes to the law will be decided when he returns to Victoria after a 10-day tour
through the United States.
In New York, Brendan Donohoe, 7 News.