for the last three years we've been
getting things done we're building the
big road and rail projects our state
needs upgrading and building new schools
across Victoria ending the ambulance
crisis and saving the TAFE system and
we've created hundreds of thousands of
Victorian jobs our state is finally
moving again but a strong economy in a
growing Victoria has to work for
everyone
we can't leave anyone behind that's why
we're making things fair providing fast
quality health care for every Victoria
wherever they live giving every child
the best education helping first
homebuyers compete against cashed-up
investors and always putting Victorian
industry and Victorian workers first
these are my priorities and my
government will fight every day to
deliver where you want Pete Victoria's
strong and
you