We are Victoria. We are world-class. Australian
leaders. Entrepreneurs. Artists. Innovators.
We've had to work hard to get where we are
today, a place alive with energy where incredible
things happen every day and where there's
always something new on the menu. We now compete
on the global stage more than ever before.
So it's time to share our story with the world.
Until now, we've told our story in many different
ways. Different brands, different pieces of
the puzzle that make up our state, too often
competing with each other for attention. Brand
Victoria is a way to unify  our story.
A story of diversity and economic
strength, the best city home to the best events
where the world comes to do business because
the best minds help make our state number
one. There's so much to be proud of. The best
of everything, all in one place –
Brand Victoria.