TBMs are used around the world
including London,
New York,
Malaysia,
and Singapore.
The rotating cutter head excavates through the ground.
A conveyor belt or pipe carries the excavated rock and soil to the back of the tunnel boring machine.
Vehicles can then transport the material out of the tunnel.
Precast concrete segments line and support the tunnel floor.
TBMs can measure more than 100 metres in length,
move about 10 metres per day,
and weigh up to 1,000 tonnes.
Construction on this massive city-shaping project begins soon
with the tunnelling work starting in 2018.
Melbourne needs the Metro Tunnel
and the best construction companies in the world will build it.