It's not just the physical injuries – you
have to learn to cope with that.
It's the sheer waste and the stench of alcohol that stays with you.
PHONE: I'm just ringing to inform you that your daughter Lucy has been involved in a car accident.
You'll need to come down.
MAN: This is not even about her, you know – the car's smashed.
(Inaudible)
MAN: This is the driver.
DOCTOR: That looks very messy.
DOCTOR: You can't go in there at the moment, mate.
MAN: I've got to go in there.
DOCTOR: Want to come with us?
We'll just have a chat to you for a second.
MOTHER: Is she alright?
DOCTOR: She's okay for the moment.
DOCTOR: Her left leg has been damaged quite severely.
There's a possibility that she may lose that leg.
DOCTOR: We'll also scan her head to look at whether there's any head injury as well.
KAREN: They drink too much, and then they drive.
They smash up their cars and the people they're supposed to care about.
And if they survive, they're the ones that have to live with that.
And that's the real tragedy.
If you drink, then drive, you're a bloody idiot.