the AFL multicultural round brings
together our greatest asset and our
greatest game we love our sport not only
on the big stage but also in our
neighborhoods our local clubs our parks
and backyards sport and any level brings
us together as a community and ours is a
palace diverse a community as you can
find its new Australians and Australians
have been here for 60 thousand years and
it's something we have to embrace
because it's a part of who we are
everyone here has a right to belong and
be included and everyone should embrace
diversity I thank the AFL and everybody
who's involved in this great game
serving this great purpose
Not authorised by the Victorian Government 1
Treasury place Melbourne