Qantas has confirmed it will use Melbourne
as a training base for pilots on its new 787s
ahead of their delivery next year. It came
as the Premier marked a Victorian manufacturing
milestone at Boeing's headquarters near Seattle.
State political reporter Andrew Lund.
Boeing's Everett Factory is the world's biggest building
by volume, but to build the high-tech 787,
the company relies on help from Melbourne.
Boeing Australia builds important components for the 787. The flaps at the trailing edge of the wing are an
important component to the aerodynamics.
It's a Victorian manufacturing
success story the Premier was keen to promote
as he was given a guided tour of the giant
plant, his visit coinciding with the 500th
shipment from Melbourne.
Without the high-tech expertise of Melbourne workers, the Dreamliner simply wouldn't get off the ground.
Earlier this year, Boeing announced plans to cut thousands
of jobs from its commercial aircraft division.
But after meeting with company executives,
Daniel Andrews is confident the Fishermans
Bend plant and its 1200 employees have a bright future.
Something like $500 million worth of investment in the last 15 years. They're here to stay.
Qantas has ordered 8 of the
787-9 variant and has confirmed it will use
a high-tech simulator based in Melbourne to help train its pilots.
Just to have a terrific simulator in Melbourne, we want to use that to its maximum capacity.
Qantas is due to take delivery of its first Dreamliner in the second half of next year. The airline says
it's still working to finalise the aircraft's
interior fit out and is yet to confirm exactly
where it will fly. The Government hopes the
Victorian components will make regular returns
to Melbourne as the new planes open up links
with the rest of the world.
In Seattle, Andrew Lund, Nine News.