The Victorian Government will partner with
Transurban to build the Western Distributor.
Together with the Monash Freeway upgrade,
this will streamline the M1 from Geelong to
Pakenham. This massive project will provide
a much-needed alternative to the West Gate
Bridge and create 5,600 jobs. The project
will include widening the West Gate Freeway
from 8 to 12 lanes, a tunnel under Yarraville,
a bridge over the Maribyrnong and direct access
to the Port of Melbourne, an elevated road
along Footscray Road, an interchange with
CityLink and access to the city. The Western
Distributor will slash travel times by up
to 20 minutes, take up to 6,000 trucks off
the West Gate Bridge and up to 6,000 trucks
off local streets in the inner west, as well
as completing the Federation Trail for cyclists.
Community consultation will guide the final
design. Construction on the Monash Freeway
section will start in 2016 with the Western
Distributor starting in 2018. The Western
Distributor will cut travel times and create
thousands of jobs for Victorians.