The Royal Children's will team up with the
Boston Children's Hospital to help improve
care for sick kids. Hospital chief Christine
Kilpatrick flew to the United States to make
the announcement alongside Premier Daniel Andrews.
State political reporter Andrew Lund was there.
Armed with dozens of koalas and
kangaroos, Daniel Andrews discovered Boston
kids can be tough customers.
I got another stuffed animal in my bag.
The Premier was visiting the Boston Children's Hospital to mark a new partnership with
the Royal Children's Hospital in Melbourne.
There's no doubt in medicine and in health generally today it's all about collaboration.
We have a whole set of digital
opportunities, telehealth opportunities,
communications that were never available before.
And so crossing that great ocean is going
to be much easier than in the past.
The two hospitals plan
to collaborate to improve safety
and quality standards as well as
expanding their education offering.
Dedicated to improving the lives of children
from prevention all the way
through the most complex care.
Boston is a world-leader in medical research. This
facility has used zebra fish to unlock treatments
for cancer and muscular dystrophy. The State
Government hopes Victoria can tap into that knowledge.
There are eight important memorandums
of understanding, so important deals that
formalise partnerships, take partnerships
to the next level. The Government has also
The Government has also announced an $80 million joint enterprise between Monash University and
the University of Melbourne designed to accelerate the development of new medicines.
The partnership is expected
to generate around $360 million worth of activity
over the next decade, which the Government
says will support the development of new companies
and jobs, as well as inreased investment and exports.
We have some of the best science
anywhere in the world, some of the best people
who are doing great work. We need to keep
more of that value chain in our local area.
In Boston, Andrew Lund, Nine News.