Located just 2 kilometres from the CBD,
Arden will be a global commerical precinct that will provide a legacy for the state.
It will have excellent transport connections
and be a gateway to Parkville,
the CBD,
and Melbourne's flourishing west.
At the heart of the precinct will be a bustling new train station due to open by 2026.
It is envisioned that this area will be developed gradually  over the next 30 years.
The government owns much of the land in Arden,
so it has a unique opportunity to ensure
its urban renewal is guided by world's best practice in planning and design.
We are sure with careful planning and community input,
it will become a destination we can all be proud of.