My name is Simon.
Angel.
Angus.
My name is Nome.
Doing maths.
Doing reading.
Because there are all my favourite pictures or words.
Making sounds and spelling them.
You can learn what two plus eight is.
No.
She helped me do all the words and
learning.
He did a funny face.
He can draw love hearts and flowers beautiful.
Let us play games.
Seeing our friends again.
They teach me how to play the game
of tiggy, because I don't know what tiggy is.
Normally me and Logan play football with Tamsin
in grade one
or two.
If someone touches us, it means we have to catch them as fast as we can.
If we touch them, it means it's their turn to catch us.
No.
ALL: Thank you!