the design and builder has been chosen
for Melbourne 2nd river crossing the
Westgate tunnel project will slash
congestion and provide a new tunnel and
vital alternative to the West Gate
Bridge communities will benefit from an
improved interchange from the West more
lanes on the Westgate freeway including
express lanes to and from the city and
better noise protection along the
freeway a redesigned longer tunnel that
moves the exits further away from home
and new twin tunnels connecting to a
second river crossing to get people to
where they need to go almost nine
hectares of new open space including
parks and wetlands more than 14
kilometres of new and upgraded walking
and cycling park including a new express
Feliway along Footscray road to the CBD
and new truck band for greater community
safety the Westgate tunnel project will
create thousands of jobs cut travel time
and take trots off local streets less
time in traffic means more time
where you want to be authorised by
Victorian Government 1 Treasury place
Melbourne