The Mernda rail extension will meet the needs
of one of Victoria's fastest growing regions
by helping to connect local people to work, study
and important services right across Melbourne.
The project will extend the South Morang
rail line with the construction of 8 kilometres
of new railway to the proposed Mernda Town Centre.
And it will feature three new state-of-the-art stations.
We've developed a design that
reflects local feedback by including
an additional station at Hawkestowe
that the community asked for,
providing 2000 carparks,
400 more than originally planned,
and by keeping the majority of
the new rail at ground level.
We're improving walking and cycling
connectivity with a new shared used path,
connecting South Morang to Mernda
and all the stations in between.
The new station at Marymede
will be built at ground level
and will connect into the local
walking and cycling path network.
It has a spacious landscaped forecourt,
which offers a series of relaxing spaces to meet
before catching the train.
The new line passes under busy
Plenty Road as it heads further north.
Through the use of two underpasses
and three rail bridges,
the Mernda rail extension avoids
the construction of any level crossings.
A new station at Hawkestowe will have
up to 350 parking spaces for commuters
and provide uninterrupted views over Plenty Gorge Park.
Sensitive urban design and landscaping
near residential areas will minimise noise
and improve amenity for the local community.
Neighbouring the proposed town centre,
the premium station at Mernda will provide
a fully integrated transport hub that is expected to service 5000 passengers each day.
The Mernda rail extension will
begin construction in early 2017
and will be open to commuters in 2019.