Victoria will once again become a national
leader on climate change and play its part
in a worldwide movement to reduce emissions
and keep the global temperature rise to under
2 degrees.
TAKE2 is Victoria's historic government-led
climate change pledge to reach our long-term
target of net zero emissions by 2050.
To achieve this, we must take advantage of
Victoria's existing clean energy resources
and support new energy technologies.
We need businesses to innovate and develop
industries for the future, because this will
create demand for new jobs and skills to support
our move to a low carbon economy.
All of us have a role to play and with practical
action from communities, businesses and governments
we can achieve this together.
We must take decisive action because we ignore
climate change at our peril. Future generations
of Victorians deserve a government that is
prepared for the challenges and opportunities
that lie ahead of us.
I encourage you to join us, pledge and share
it with others.
It's time for us all to act.
It's time for us all to TAKE2 now, at take2.vic.gov.au.