Metro Tunnel benefits commuters right across the network
so it doesn't matter if you're in Sunshine, Sandringham, or Seymour,
everyone benefits from the Metro Tunnel.
And it will also deliver significant extra capacity
so at the peak time, we will see an additional 39,000 commuters
use this new system every single day.
We are fully funding this project. Every single dollar.
To deliver this $10.9 billion project, it has been put into
various packages of work and we're releasing today
the contract for the biggest package of work.
It's constructing two 9 kilometre tunnels and 5 underground stations for the Metro Tunnel.
It's project that has national priority status from Infrastructure Australia.
It's the project that's going to unlock the capacity
for Victoria's entire public transport network.
Well, yesterday's announcement of the funding is actually going to
be very good timing for us because it will add a lot of confidence
to the process we're going through at the moment in trying to engage with the market
and attract as broadly as possible their interest in the project.