Melbourne is to get its own version of the
New York Police Department's high-tech crime
fighting nerve centre. The Premier and Victoria
Police have conceded they need to do more
in the fight against street gangs.
Wearing a bulletproof vest, the Premier rode along
with some of New York's finest to see how
serious they are about fighting crime.
The New York Police Department's Real Time Crime
Control Center utilises more than 8000 cameras,
including gunshot sensors and 35 different
databases to keep on top of the crooks.
And Victoria will be getting its own version of the high-tech crime fighting centre from early next year.
To make sure that our dedicated
Victoria Police have got everything they need
– resources and the intelligence, the information
and the data.
Victoria's Assistant Commissioner Debra Abbott says a new nerve centre could detect events
such as the Moomba riots.
It certainly will give us real time intelligence
and information that we currently really don't
have a handle on.
The NYPD also has a joint
operations centre used during major events,
presidential visits and public incidents.
New York City and Victoria are members of
the Strong Cities Network, which was formed
last year to share information around the
world about potential terrorism threats. Chief
Thomas Galati says more information keeps
the community and police officers as safe
as possible.
It makes the course of investigations,
of policing just in general much quicker and
much safer.
In New York,Brendan Donohoe, 7 News.