The Victorian Government is removing nine
dangerous and congested level crossings and
rebuilding five stations along Melbourne's
busiest train line, the Cranbourne-Pakenham line.
Boom gates can be down for up to 87
minutes during the two-hour morning peak,
crippling the road network, dividing communities
and putting safety at risk.
Getting rid of these relics of the past will improve safety
and reduce congestion.
By separating the road and rail network through three sections of elevated rail,
this innovative and modern design will remove the barrier between communities and create 225,000 square metres
of linear park, equivalent to over 11 MCGs. With new
community spaces and parklands, and new carparking,
the existing rail corridor will be opened
up to the community and transformed into a vibrant public space.
A new pedestrian and
bicycle network will connect 12 kilometres
of continual paths and include up to seven
new community activity spaces.
The innovative design significant reduces
the impact of construction. The new rail line
can be constructed while trains are still
running, greatly minimising the impact on
both road and rail users. The new Murrumbeena
Station will be integrated with the existing
village precinct with improved interchanges
between transport modes and bicycle facilities
to promote active communities. The design
minimises impacts on the local environment
by retaining large amounts of mature and locally-significant vegetation.
At Clayton Station, the design solution creates new community open spaces,
an open civic plaza and an integrated bus
interchange that will improve connections
to Monash Health and Monash University's Clayton campus.
The elevated rail allows for new car parking to be introduced across the whole
project corridor, including over 300 car parks
around Clayton Station. The proposed design
delivers a new Noble Park Station closer to
Heatherton Road to better integrate with the
Douglas Street activity centre. The design
makes it easier for pedestrians to get to
the Noble Park RSL, the Aquatic Centre and
Ross Reserve. A new road from Leonard Avenue
to Ian Street will connect the northern and
southern precincts. A new village plaza and
station forecourt with public seating will
be large enough to accomodate community activities.
The design will reduce the overall noise from trains.
It will deliver a more reliable train service with a 42% increase in capacity.
The project will create 2,000 jobs and fully open in 2018.
Removing these nine level crossings, building five new stations and opening up communities
will reduce traffic congestion, improve safety and improve the way in which we live.