My name is Rowena Allen. I'm Victoria's first
Commissioner for Gender and Sexuality. So
basically that means I work with lesbian,
gay, bisexual, trans, gender diverse and
intersex Victorians. I'm excited about how
the position of Gender and Sexuality Commissioner
has been warmly welcomed in Victoria. It's
a fantastic state to live with such a progressive
government that is being so inclusive and
welcoming for LGBTI Victorians. I've been
an advocate in the LGBTI space for the last
20 years and I started the first support group
for rural same-sex attracted young people
in Victoria up in Shepparton. My job is one
of education and advocacy, and doing that,
I work with sporting groups, corporate groups,
community groups right across Victoria to
make sure we make Victoria a really safe place
to live. I've had a lot of contact from people
in other states about how they get a Commissioner
for Gender and Sexuality – Victoria is absolutely
leading the way in inclusive practice.