Michelle and I had been together two years.
We decided that we wanted to move in together
and yeah we bought the land out at Berwick
and decided to build a house. So I was kinda
lucky that with NDIS helping set up the house
with the modifications and doorways being
widened. The ensuite bathroom was completely
changed around to be able to allow an open
shower. There’s handrails in both bathrooms.
They’ve also paid to have the kitchen bench
to be lowered and extended to allow me to
do things at the sink.
When I did my interview with the case planner,
you know he asked me do I drive and I’m
like, no, and he’s like, well why not? So
I went and had some driving lessons and started
driving again just using a spinner knob modification
on the steering wheel. We can go on holidays
now and you know not have to worry about sort
of having personal support and things like that.
I think that that’s a big thing for
me has always been getting that independence
to be able to sort of live the life that I
want to live.