We're getting on with the job.
And this year's Budget delivers on the things
that really matter.
We're building better roads
and public transport.
Because Victorians need options
they can rely on, wherever they live.
We're removing more level crossings.
Making more trains and trams for Victorians
in Victoria.
And we're building new roads to make your drive
safer and faster.
Victoria now leads the nation in jobs growth
and we'll create even more across the state.
We'll make sure every region shares in our
success
and we'll revive regional rail to connect
communities and create more jobs.
We'll ease the burden on small business
and we'll keep investing in skills, apprentices
and attracting new industries and new jobs.
In an emergency, all we want is for our families
to get fast and first-class care.
That's why we're delivering better hospitals
shorter waiting lists
and an ambulance service Victorians can count on.
There will be thousands more police on the
beat as well
with the powers and the equipment they need
to fight crime and keep Victoria safe.
We're putting more teachers into better classrooms.
Upgrading and building new schools right across Victoria.
And for our youngest Victorians, we're making
sure our kinders are properly funded.
And that every child gets the best start in
life.
I promised I would do everything I could to
keep women and their children safe.
That I would change it all when it comes to
family violence.
And that's what this budget does.
Protecting the vulnerable
punishing the guilty.
There's more in this year's budget than ever
before to deal with the number one law and
order issue in our state and in our nation.
And that is family violence.
More jobs.
Better schools.
World-class hospitals.
More police on the beat.
Better roads.
And public transport that actually works.
These are the things that really matter.
For every Victorian, wherever you live.
That's what we were elected to do.
And we are getting on with the job.