Premier Daniel Andrews has landed in Seattle
to begin a 9-day tour of America. He used
a visit to Microsoft to unveil a partnership
designed to inspire more Victorian students
into the booming IT sector. State political
reporter Andrew Lund is in the United States.
Dodging flying fish became the latest hazard
of Victoria's top job.
One more! One more!
As the Premier touched down in Seattle, a
city with football on the front page and its
own version of skyrail.
You'll see elevated rail in all the great cities of the world and that's why Melbourne needs it also.
Seattle is also home to tech giant Microsoft and the
sprawling headquarters was the first official
stop for Daniel Andrews.
You can imagine customers in a retailer using this stuff to try on clothes virtually.
The Premier met junior high students learning coding, seen by many as the language of the future.
It's not exactly Java, but it's not exactly C++, so it's kind of like Scratch.
He announced plans for an Australian-first
coding contest, giving Victorian students
in years 6, 8 and 10 the opportunity to pitch
ideas for apps or games in the hope of inspiring
the next Bill Gates.
I think the chances are pretty ding dang good actually. We've seen lots of great ideas coming from young people.
The Premier is due to meet the Microsoft president
later in his trip, which will take him from
Seattle to New York, Boston, San Francisco and Los Angeles.
It's going to be a very important trip with a lot of positive announcements.
I'm getting younger! There you go. Very good.
In Seattle, Andrew Lund, Nine News.