the biggest public transport project in
history is coming to Victoria
[Music]
suburban rail loop is a new underground
rail network connecting Melbourne
suburbs it will link every major rail
line from the Frankston line all the way
to arabi
making it easier to get around Melbourne
between suburbs and to the airport
starting their Cheltenham it will
connect the southeastern train lines
with potential stations at Clayton
Monash Glen Waverley Burwood and Box
Hill heading towards the airport it will
travel under the northern suburbs with
potential connections at Doncaster
Heidelberg bandura reservoir Falkner
and Broadmeadows
it will connect to the new airport Rail
Link
traveling from the airport to sunshine
and then completing the ring of our
suburbs on the Werribee line the
suburban rail loop includes connections
to major jobs precincts universities and
tapes hospitals and retail centers new
regional rail interchanges will be to
connect regional commuters to every
corner of Melbourne without having to
travel into the city when complete it
will carry 400,000 passengers a day
taking thousands of people of existing
city bound trains and 200,000 vehicles
of congested roads it'll create more
than 20,000 jobs during construction and
even more after it
it's the biggest transport project in
Australian history the project our
modern growing Victorian needs