[Music]
[Applause]
you
[Music]
[Applause]
melbourne garden city of the garden
state an orderly city of charm and
beauty a busy city of progress and
people it is a big city big in size big
in population but it has its problems
moving people to and from work and
around the city every day is one of them
more and more people placing more and
more strain on transport systems
overcrowded trams trains and buses daily
traffic jams the rush rush rush to beat
the clock the frustration of holdups
congestion the surface affected beneath
this sprawling severe drama is taking
place a drama which will reshape the
Metropolitan transport system the
Melbourne underground rail loop it's
vital purpose is to expand present
facilities not just to meet the needs of
today but to cope with the demands of
tomorrow the loop is not a separate
railway under the city but an
underground extension of the existing
suburban rail system there will be three
underground stations Parliament Museum
and Flagstaff linked to Spencer Street
and Flinders Street princes bridge
stations all suburban tracks except the
some Kilda and Port Melbourne lines will
have direct access to the loop tracks
and in addition there will be city
circle trains providing a continuous
service around the loop
[Music]
train travelers said by five city
stations will have convenient access to
business and commercial houses and shops
in the city and adjacent districts
designing planning and construction is
mammoth this is a cut and cover
operation where a gigantic pit has been
dug from the surface the removal of
buildings and the diversion of traffic
was only the beginning to make way for
the engineers and a task force of
workers for making a complex ambitious
and major investment into a reality
construction of the loop started in 1971
it is changing the face of mobile tens
of thousands of tons of Earth have been
gouged for the museum station site to
make way for foundations and buildings
[Music]
the look is not simply one underground
channel there are for each linking the
five city stations and designed to serve
a specific group of suburban railway
lines
[Applause]
already real shapes are emerging
behind the frontline troops the 1,500
workers who are mining and building
tunneling and constructing are the
backroom boys the engineers the
architects and draftsman plan every
detail and supervise every step with
intricate care and infinite patience
[Music]
there's a universal fascination in
trains model or life size their
assassination - in the integration of a
ground-level rail system and one deep
below the surface the top end of column
Street is seeing changes but around the
corner 38 meters below Spring Street
change is even more spectacular with
construction of the lower platforms of
Parliament Station well advanced an
architects model highlights features of
one entry to the city's transport system
a huge and vital investment in the
future an investment which will produce
dividends of streamline travel for the
people of Melbourne
[Music]
stations are as long as a city block so
placement of entrances and exits must
suit the convenience of travellers
[Music]
[Applause]
the Minister for transport and the
chairman of the authority are frequent
visitors to the project progress can
readily be inspected from one of the
narrow gauge work trains
[Applause]
[Music]
Flinders Street is seeing its share of
change including an overpass for two
additional rail tracks
[Music]
Flagstaff station progresses platforms
the escalators concourses stairs and
reps
[Applause]
[Music]
deep underground engineering skill
reflected in rugged symmetry competes
for attention with the work of the
artist on the surface
Moomba a time for getting together and
having fun for looking at the work of
local artists for spending leisure time
and the bright sun
[Music]
only meters away in the darkness below
bro taking pick machines with teeth
harder than steel continue an
unrelenting drive toward the day of
completion
the staccato of pneumatic rules shatters
the Uranus as man and his tools come to
grips with the Earth's solid toughness
built in Melbourne the full-face
tunnel-boring machine aptly called the
mole uses its 60 disk cutters to
excavate a 7 meter circle in solid rock
at every turn that's giant cut ahead
[Music]
[Applause]
breakthrough with shattering force in a
crash of rock the mole breaks through to
the draft relief shot
[Music]
[Applause]
there is much to be done with the
flexibility provided by the loop and
extra tracks on suburban lines
greatly increased capacity will be
available to the Melbourne railway
system more expressive reduction in
travel time better and faster train
services
there is overhead wiring to be installed
retaining walls to be built
signal gantry is to be erected ramps and
box tunnels to be completed tracks to be
layed more rolling stock to be built
[Applause]
additional communications equipment in
an era of electronics the project is an
exemplification of cooperation and
coordination on a grand scale between
one and a half thousand people of many
disciplines
[Applause]
a glimpse of the future below the
surface for members of the public during
a Melbourne underground rail loop
Authority open day
[Music]
[Applause]
above ground there is ample evidence of
activity and the pattern of programs
[Applause]
[Music]
machines Rumble and digg'd invite men
plan and strive and sweat
[Music]
around the clock the unremitting task
goes on towards the reward of conclusion
and completion in the early 1980s by the
Melbourne underground rail loop
authority of an underworld artery which
will carry moblins railway system into
the 21st century
[Music]
you