To help make your drive times smoother
and safer on the M80 Ring Road,
we're delivering a $300 million upgrade
from Sunshine Avenue to the Calder Freeway,
which will cut your travel time by 15 minutes.
We're adding two lanes each way
to get rid of the bottlenecks at
Sunshine Avenue, Keilor Park Drive
and the Calder Freeway.
Without disrupting traffic in peak periods,
we're widening the EJ Whitten Bridge
to provide five lanes in each direction.
Public safety barriers, similar to those on the West Gate,
will make the bridge safer for pedestrians and cyclists.
And a new freeway management system
will provide you with better information
so you can spend less time in traffic
and more time where you need to be.