well if we want to prepare students for
the future the future for work then this
is where it all begins
on the assistant principal here at
lyndale secondary college at current
buildings date back to nineteen sixty
one they've basically been wearing out
they built for different time and place
currently our instrumental music staff
operate out of portables education moved
on since then so we've got building
approval for stem building which
incorporates science technology
engineering and maths and for performing
arts building a new canteen and you've
seen your study center there's been a
lot of positive thoughts regarding you
know James molino and Daniel Andrews
promoting Victoria's the education state
we're looking forward to buildings that
actually cater for 21st century learners
authorised by the Victorian Government 1
Treasury place Melbourne