The Western Distributor will provide a vital
second river crossing while saving 20 minutes
when travelling from the west.
Ongoing design work and feedback from communities,
councils and industry has been incorporated
into the project's reference design.
Congestion and traffic flow along the West
Gate Freeway will be improved by widening
from 8 to 12 lanes. A new road layout including
express lanes to the West Gate bridge will
improve reliability and reduce travel times.
A connection a Hyde St moves trucks directly
between local industry and the freeway.
The design includes a seamless entry and exit
to the Western Distributor tunnel with portals
within the West Gate freeway, taking trucks
off local roads in the inner west and will
provide direct access to Australia's busiest
container port meaning more efficient movement
of goods. The project's urban design strategy
responds to feedback and will enhance the
places through which it passes. An elevated
section along Footscray Road will provide
access to East Swanston Dock, City Link and
City North, taking through traffic out of
the CBD and supporting new job precincts.
And the project will now include nearly 10kms
of new and upgraded cycling and walking paths.
There will be more opportunities to have your
say about this design and innovative solutions
by tenderers for the construction of Melbourne's
Western Distributor.