MEG: The message that I would give to new patients
would be to take each day, each diagnosis, each treatment at a time.
Not to worry too much about what might happen, not worry about the what ifs.
CLARE: You're in the best possible place with the best possible people, the best possible research
and you'll be able to help you achieve the best possible outcomes for you.
JOHN: Cancer patients, in my experience,
are the most patient, tolerant people in the world.
And we all want it to happen tomorrow, but it ain't gonna happen tomorrow.
And we're going to be patient and wait for it to happen.
MEG: My message to all staff would be
to listen to your patients,
to treat them as the people that they are,
not the diagnosis, not the patients that you might see in front of you.
Each of them has their own story, their own life, their own family, their own backgrounds.
Think about them as people.
JOHN: Peter Mac is working wonders.
I call my case a miracle.
This place can work miracles.
Never give up hope.
I'm way out there on a limb.
There's nothing out here – except this place.
And this is my future.
And that's what I wrote on a rock, a message for lots of people.
This place is my future. It's my future life.