The business case clearly shows that this
is a project of great strength. It stacks
up, even on the most conservative of measures.
This is the best part of 4,000 jobs in Victoria,
39,000 extra passengers able to move through
the rail network every morning peak. This
is a really significant project and now, it's
time for us to have a true partnership between
our government, the Federal Government and
the private sector to be able to deliver this
and deliver it well. We've contributed $4.5
billion to this project and we'd like the
Federal Government to consider the business
case, to look at the positive benefits that
come from this amazing project, and to be
a partner with us. New York, Tokyo, London,
Paris – all of these cities are making these
sorts of investments or already have so that
they can have a turn up and go public transport
system. No need for a timetable – services
are so regular that you can simply arrive and get first class public transport where you need to go.
As well as being a project
that unlocks the core of our public transport
network, this is indeed a public transport
infrastructure project for the whole of the
state. There are benefits for the outer suburbs
that are growing quickly. For regional Victorians,
they will have access to the Parkville precinct,
the important medical and education precinct.
They'll be able to catch a train there for
the first time. You'll be able to get on a
train in Gippsland, get on a train in Ballarat
and come into that precinct in a way people
have not been able to access before. These
are just some of the many examples of why
we need to push on with Melbourne Metro to
deliver more services, but also increase reliability
across our public transport system.