firstly can I thank you very much for
your warm welcome it is a great honor a
privilege to be here today I want to
begin my remarks by of course
acknowledging the traditional owners of
this land and poem I do personal
respects to elder's past the president
to each and every member of Aboriginal
communities across our state this is an
historic occasion one that is well
overdue and one that confirms beyond any
doubt I think that in Victoria more than
anywhere else in our nation we
understand we embrace we own and we are
committed to making real that central
truth that better outcomes for
Aboriginal people must be led by
Aboriginal people those words are
uttered often and in many different
forms but here in Victoria all of us can
be abundantly proud but that's not just
a value statement we are living that and
making that real and that is something
that is a great source of pride for
myself for Gavin for Natalie for every
member of our team I want to acknowledge
Jill Gallagher and her work I've known
Jill for a long time and I credit Jill
with my appreciation of that central
truth we first worked together when I
was Health Minister and she was of
course at botch oh and she taught me in
very practical terms that we can't have
we can't have decisions being made that
directly impact Aboriginal families and
communities without a strong Aboriginal
voice in not just the process but in the
active decision-making that is true in
health it's true in so many different
sectors and it's true when it comes to
the notion of making self-determination
real not just fine words but indeed a
process that will not be easy it will be
challenging it will test us it will push
us it will
time to time be very difficult I expect
but we're not here because this is an
easy process if it were easy it would
perhaps have been delivered many many
years ago it wasn't but are now forced
to us this unique opportunity to do more
to do better to deal with all of those
challenges that will come along the way
and if I might be permitted to make a
fairly parochial point as a state we are
I think at our best when we lead our
nation and for some unknown reason we as
a nation find it difficult to do
meaningful things with that wonderful
truth-telling poetry that is that all
the rest even we find it as a nation
impossible to do what all of you have
done come here with different
perspectives with different voices with
different lived experience but United in
a common purpose that we have to
together do everything we can to heal
the wounds of the past and we have to
build a shared common future one that is
hopeful one that is realistic at the
same time but one that is truly about
self-determination the alternative is to
skirt around these issues never finding
the courage to lead never finding the
courage to face up to those terrible
injustice 'as of the past now I want to
say a couple things about where we are
today and I know that for many this is a
symbol of injustice this building 163
years of injustice but as Jill I think
very eloquently made the point yesterday
it's fitting that a reset of this
partnership a reset of our relationship
and our way forward should arrive from
this place should should come from this
place and I am determined as every
member of the government and through the
government every Victorian to a much
more honest and much more just a much
more include
and respectful future and as difficult
as it is to perhaps be in this building
we will look back I think he needs to
come and be very proud of what has been
achieved to this point and all that will
come thereafter to each of you can I say
thank you for your leadership in
individual communities and I thank you
those who went through the democratic
election process can I thank you it's
not easy to run for public office many
of us know that all of us now know that
it can be very challenging there are
many different views there are many
different opinions but it's only by
taking a stand it's only by putting
yourself forward that we can hope to
find that consensus find an agreement
that is about yes the past and terrible
awful things that dominate our history
but also find that shared connection and
bond and that unified position to take
us forward
now I'm abundantly conscious as well
that this Q&A at the end of this so long
speeches are never good speeches but I
want to get to that as quickly as I can
but I just hope that I leave you with a
clear sense that we have embarked on
this process because each of you and
through you Aboriginal communities
across the state said that no
self-determination conversation would be
complete or it would simply be a
conversation words without action unless
treaty was on the table and unless we
took big and bold steps to deliver
treaty that's what brings us here today
listening to Aboriginal people nothing
about this process will be easy nothing
about this process will be quick but
important work really is I want to thank
you for your leadership I want to thank
you for your participation for your
commitment with this opportunity comes
great responsibility for each of you and
for us and for our part I commit the
government its agencies I commit all of
- doing everything we can to get us to a
place where in decades to come we can
look back with a real sense of pride and
purpose and know that this day was true
national leadership that this day
started a process that got us to a more
decent future a more honest future a
future that's about shared connection a
celebration of our rich history all 40
50 60 thousand years of it while facing
up to the terrible injustice of the past
giving not just a voice but real power
to Aboriginal people and building a
better Victoria that is not just good
for Aboriginal Victorians that is a more
fair just decent and inclusive Victoria
for all Victorians this work is being
led by Aboriginal people but the
beneficiaries are a much broader group
they are in fact every single Victorian
and for that I am proud and very
grateful to you thank you very much
[Applause]