today I'm very pleased to make two
significant announcements firstly we
have bought forward 40 million dollars
of that three hundred million dollars in
planning that will be available right
now to make sure that the planning work
is done the balance of the money will be
delivered in the very first budget of
our government as we outlined but the
bring forward of that money means that
planning work doesn't have to wait until
the beginning of the new financial year
the second announcement today beyond the
bring forward of that 40 million dollars
is the Melbourne Metro Rail Authority
this is going to be the dedicated focus
the expertise the hard work that is
necessary to make this very big project
the reality that Victorians want it to
be this is effectively a second city
look this is five brand-new stations
it's 20,000 extra passenger movements in
the morning peak and the afternoon peak
it's a train system and a public
transport system in many respects where
no timetable is needed this is about
making sure that the world's most
livable city has a 21st century public
transport system it is a nine to eleven
billion dollar project that's the
numbers that infrastructure Australia
have put on it it remains infrastructure
Australia's number one infrastructure
priority for our state
it is three and a half thousand jobs it
is a very significant undertaking it's
the biggest investment the biggest
transformation of our public transport
system since the original city loop was
constructed in the early 80s
what we're announcing today is the
bringing forward of 40 million dollars
of our 300 million dollars
commitment to this project to undertake
the detail planning work that is just so
vital to make sure this project is
delivered within the time frames that we
need it to be so we're establishing the
Melbourne Metro authority that authority
will oversee the finalization of the
business case there is work to be done
to refresh that business case and make
sure that alongside of that the detailed
planning work has done the engineering
work has done the site assessments done
and also importantly to the community
consultation is undertaken on the
finalization of the the route and the
design that is a big job and that's why
we don't want to waste one single moment
in getting this project underway
you