The State Government is funding the Mernda Rail extension project.
From South Morang Station, the railway will continue
for approximately 8 kilometres to Mernda.
Most of the railway will travel along the ground.
A new walking and cycling path, along with several crossings
will open up the area, complementing City of Whittlesea's
proposed path nework, eventually creating a continuous link
along the corridor from South Morang to Mernda.
A station will be built near Marymede Catholic College
with up to 500 car parks, and a kiss-and-ride.
As part of the project, bidders will be required to investigate
and price the proposed station near Hawkstowe Parade.
The bridge over Simon Creek, the Yan Yean Bridge, the Pine Track, and the Parkway
will protect the creek and the surrounding local environment
providing connectivity. The premium station at Mernda
will be located on the south side of Bridge Inn Road,
and will integrate with a proposed town centre and the transport hub.