The Victorian Government is widening and upgrading
the Monash Freeway as part of the Western
Distributor project. The project includes
a 44-kilometre upgrade along the Monash Freeway
between Chadstone and Pakenham to help cut
traffic congestion and get you home sooner
and safer. 30 kilometres of additional lanes,
widening from four to five lanes between EastLink
and South Gippsland Freeway, and two to three
lanes from South Gippsland Freeway to Clyde
Road. This will cut congestion on the Monash
and save 10 minutes in travel time per day.
Ramp signals will control the flow of traffic
entering the freeway while overhead electronic
signs and smart technology, such as automatic
incident detection, will help to keep traffic
moving, to ease congestion and assist with
reliability during an incident. Together with
the Western Distributor, this network-wide
solution will reduce congestion, improve safety
and reliability, and streamline traffic from
Geelong to Pakenham.