today we're announcing 100 million
dollars in new money to bring forward
the planning not of one or two of these
50 but of all 50 level crossings that
are holding us back something as
significant as this also requires a
dedicated focus and that's why we're
also announcing today along with that
one hundred million dollars in new money
on this program we're also announcing
the level crossing removal Authority a
dedicated team of experts engineers
surveyors all those who've got the
skills and the knowledge and the
understanding to make sure that we get
on and deliver on our commitment in full
on time and get the best value for
Victorian taxpayers so this is all about
better and safer roads people being able
to move throughout the community that
they've helped to build so it's about
dealing with congestion improving safety
creating jobs but also they shouldn't
forget this will allow us to run more
trains more often if you were to run
additional trains without removing these
level crossings then in many instances
boom gates would be down for 50 minutes
across the morning and afternoon peaks
that would be a completely unacceptable
set of circumstances we'd finish up with
absolute traffic chaos this is a really
exciting and ambitious agenda this is
about addressing congestion issues it's
about improving safety it's also about
looking at how we can put more train
services into our public transport
system to provide additional services
for passengers right across Melbourne
but it's also about looking at other
economic development opportunities and
that's a tremendously exciting part of
this project the project itself is going
to create around four and a half
thousand jobs but we want to look at how
we can work with businesses communities
around each of the level crossings about
how we can capture more job
opportunities and that's what the
authority a very important part
the authorities work will be about
working at the local level as well as
having that doing the big picture work
on the business plan and looking at how
we're going to get those 50 level
crossings removed across the Melbourne
rail network over the next eight years