The Victorian people elected us to rebuild
schools and hospitals, cut congestion and
create more jobs.
That's what really matters.
And we’re getting it done.
We’re not going to sit on the sidelines.
Instead we're creating thousands of jobs by getting
on with the projects our state needs.
And we’re working with businesses directly
– helping them get the investment they need
to create new jobs, and helping Victorians
get the skills they need to fill them.
That starts at school.
We’re funding the biggest investment in
new school buildings in Victorian history.
Because our kids won’t get a first-rate
education in a second-rate classroom.
We’re funding special schools, too - because
every student deserves every chance.
We're upgrading hospitals, making sure more
people get the surgery they need sooner.
And cutting waiting times in the emergency
department. Because we all need a health system we can rely on.
Something else we all rely on is of course
our transport system.
And we’re funding a massive investment in
roads and public transport too.
It’s all about getting you home safer and
sooner, and giving you more options to get
from A to B.
Everyone has a right to safety.
Family violence is the biggest law and
order issue confronting our nation.
We made a huge change – funding an unprecedented
$572 million to keep women and children safe
and to punish the perpetrators of this hideous
crime. And we’re also working hard to make our
whole state safer as well, recruiting more
police and giving them the powers and resources
they need to fight crime and keep Victoria
safe.
We care about the things that matter most
to Victorians – jobs, health, education,
transport and quality of life.
There’s a lot of work to do.
And we are getting it done.