hi I'm dad andrew is the premier of
Victorian leader of the Labour Party
this is our first periscope press
conference it's a press conference
without any journalists so you can see
why we might do a lot of these in coming
weeks and months no no it's always got
to talk to journalists but it's even
better sometimes to talk to Victorians
about obviously the budget but also
their take on things and there's lots of
questions already come through just a
bit of housekeeping I'd ask people to
twin 22 hashtag ask the premier and the
be from time to time some things that
are perhaps can't give you all the
detail to take too long to do it but if
you go to premier geoau you'll be able
to follow the links to the budget this
year and be able to look at all the
different information that's there about
the investments were making now I don't
want to talk for too long on any one
particular subject we want to keep this
moving as fast as we can I'm told this
is something that is a first for
certainly Victorian politics and maybe
more broadly I hope to vow to do this on
a fairly regular basis it's great to be
able to answer real questions from real
people and get outside the kind of
Spring Street bubble it went all too
often caught up in just quickly this is
a budget that delivers sound financial
management that's really important if
you don't manage the state's finances
well you don't have the money to be able
to invest in the things that really
matter so there's a surplus this year
and each year over the next four and
then there's some investments that I'm
very very proud of in fact all of my
team are really proud to have made
decisions like almost four billion
dollars for our schools our kinders and
take a big boost to health really
significant boost in public transport in
fact the biggest investment in public
transport we've ever seen and then lots
of other commitments and not just in
Melbourne right across Victoria will
probably cover a little bit of that
ground as people send in their Twitter
questions let's get started that's
probably the best thing to do so the
first question comes from Jenny Ashby
and she asks when will our 196 students
know if we're getting a new school
Epsom primary now for those of you who
aren't from Epsom episodes a suburb of
Bendigo basically deterrence you've just
on the edge of Bendigo and it's part of
a really big growth corridor at the
moment we were up myself and jacinta
allan who's the local member and other
members of the team we're up there last
year making commitments to Epsom primary
skorts great teachers great kids great
parent community but the school's a bit
rundown in fact that's worse than that
it's it needs to be replaced we're
committed to do that and I'm really
pleased to tell Jenny Ashby who must be
one of the parents from Epsom or at
least she's got a close connection to
the school that the full more than five
million dollars i think 5.6 million
dollars was in today's budget and we'll
be able to begin now the planning
process so the construction can begin as
soon as possible and we can get those
kids are brand-new school for a brand
new start I think that's really
important hopefully there'll be lots of
questions about schools and education
kinders and TAFE throughout this evening
because education really is a
significant part of this budget as i
said before nearly four billion dollars
and jenny if you want your further
information you can certainly visit a
premier cup today you and there'll be
some more details but this is more than
five million for epson primary delivered
in full in the budget today Oh next one
we've got Amy Feldman only Feltman asked
me as you can see the budget is titled
for families amy has asked me she's keen
to know if singles double income no kids
or the elderly are of any interest to
the four families government I don't
know a bit more positive on these things
that it seems you are families are
that's basically all of us we're all
part of a family were all brothers and
sisters were all sons daughters partners
some of us a single and repair and some
of us are married we're all part of a
family in fact the Victorian community
is in many respects of family this is a
budget that invests for everybody and
let me just go through schools hospitals
a safer community taking real action on
family family violence investing in
better public transport investing in
better roads I think their role
to every single Victorian I think that's
the definition of fairness and Families
a better offer because of it but I mean
I don't know I've got a different view
of these things I suppose but thanks
very much for your tweet to moving on
now to TAFE David David tweets how many
years will it take the government to
repair the damage to TAFE inflicted by
the Liberals I want to thank David for
his question and I would remind him to
renew his AARP membership very very soon
David's obviously a pretty strong
supporter look I think it will take some
time it was really significant damage
but I'm very proud to have made a
promise before the election to spend
more money in TAFE to stop the cuts and
to stop that the real you know taupe
taupe was in a terrible mess it's not
fixed yet but we've kind of stabilized
these things a little bit there's more
than 300 million dollars indeed 350
million dollars in the budget delivered
today Steve who is doing a fantastic job
in this area is visited every tape
Institute across the state this money
will be shared throughout Victoria and I
just think that's fair i think that's
what a good government does don't cut
TAFE and make it harder for particularly
young people particularly those in the
outer suburbs and in regional Victoria
to get the skills that they need for the
job that they want it's a simple thing
but if you don't invest in vocational
education and training then you
compromise people's future and every
Victorian that's held back or that holds
us all back so big investment today
there'll be more next year and the year
after that and the year after that
because we value pay for me now how
important it is how long it will take to
repair the damage I suppose only bit
more positive than that David let's not
think about it in terms of damage let's
make type better than it's ever been and
today we took a very big step towards
that next Mario Grande this is a
charming why would you invest in murder
there's a bit more but that's lots of
four little i won't i won't go into that
but we made a commitment about moon
derail we took the line 22 south south
south morang and we will take it to
mandir
this is a significant investments one of
the biggest suburban rail upgrades that
the state's ever seen you've got to get
the planning right we've made that
decision today nine million dollars in
additional money to plan out the moon to
rail link and what's more from a murder
point of view I visit there quite often
and it's a great local community but it
can be better through more schools and
we're delivering those better public
transport better roads we're delivering
those also and of course taking the
pressure off health services in our
growing corridors a growth corridors is
very important as well you're not a big
moon der fan but this government
certainly is and Daniel Green is our
local members are not only a great
champion for her electorate but she
lives there she's passionate and she
makes sure i understand just how
important things are for murder and for
that whole growing north and i'm moving
on will Ross will Ross asks what were
your new LGBTI commissioners say
regarding the budgets zero dollars for
expanding overwhelmed gender dysphoria
services at the Royal Children's
Hospital in Melbourne well I don't think
we'll that will be a matter that the
LGBTI Commissioner will need to turn
their mind to because there is more
money for these gender dysphoria
services at the Royal Children's
Hospital I have had the great pleasure
of being very closely connected with the
new Royal Children's Hospital for many
years now they do great work not only
will this service this important clinic
which is a statewide service be as I
understand it the recipient of
additional funds but what's more the
Royal Children's Hospital will have a
much stronger budget because you can
have the best building you can have the
best staff and they are amazing stuff at
the Royal Children's Hospital I know
that it's a politician and in our it as
a parent too but unless they've got a
strong budget they just can't do the
work that they're trying to do so will
there is extra money there for that
service and for the Royal Children's
Hospital more broadly and I hope that's
a comfort to you and of everybody who's
appearing across our state next I've got
one here from so Tony Morton has asked
me does the new six-lane Chandler
highway breach include
full time segregated bus lines I'm not
sure about that only I think that part
of today's decision is being is that
more than a hundred million dollars to
get this project away is to do the
detailed planning to do the design to
talk to the local community I think it's
probably going to finish up being a
brand new bridge built quite close to
the current one and the current one then
can be used for all sorts of other
things whether it be bicycles
pedestrians as I've seen some ideas
about perhaps a kind of a public open
space for for markets and things there's
lots of different things you can do
their most important thing to
acknowledge is we're getting on with it
I'm sure that Fiona Richardson or make
sure we deliver a good outcome she's
been a passionate advocate on this issue
the money's there in this year's budget
planning consultation listening to the
local community will be a really
important part of it now I've got one
here from Caroline fields who says who
asks me do you think the Real Housewives
of Melbourne is a good or a bad thing
for the image of Melbourne i've not
watched the show so I don't know whether
it is or it isn't I might leave others
feel more expert yourself included
Caroline to make that judgment what I
would say the image of s States really
important and the way we project to our
region to other parts of Australia and
to the world is that's very important
because it's ultimately about whether
people are in work the visitor economy
is really important really important
this tourism and major events and all of
that sector if you're like that's 20
billion dollars a year and 200,000
Victorians whose livelihoods depend on
it this budget Toydarian dollars for a
brand new additional convention center
space so we can get all the big
conferences to come to our city those
delegates can spend their money for
hotels full bars for restaurants that's
a really important thing and then
there's 80 million dollar so we can have
a new and improved series of major
events lots of one-off events whether
it's college football baseball
basketball all of those sorts of things
and are really strong offering down at
the National Gallery error image is
important and I think that today's
budget is from a tourism and major
events point of view has really
delivered significantly to that that has
nothing to do with the Real Housewives
of Melbourne and I'm sorry I can't do
any better than that on and I think we
might be getting close to time I've got
one here from James which of your many
infrastructure projects will be started
during this term not planned but
actually started James pre best if we
get you a full list but some projects we
make no apology they're going to take
more than four years to do it melbourne
metro will not be delivered in for four
years nine kilometres attract extras 25
new underground stations a public
transport system where you can turn up
and you don't need a timetable you can
just get the next train and go that's
not for you that's not a four-year
project that's going to take much longer
than that but 1.5 billion dollars in
this year's budget we will have
delivered at least 20 of those level
crossings they'll be gone we hope to do
better if we can 20s the promise that we
made over four years and then there's a
whole range of hospitals and schools and
all sorts of other investments that will
start from this budget and we'll be
finished by the end of 2018 at least we
probably can give you a list at some
point if you go to if you had tweet me
your details and we can maybe send you
something by email or you know you two
can go to premier dr. Gupta I you and
follow the budget links if you send us
your details of maybe it's better if i
write to you with some of those answers
now I've got I think time for one more
unless is I have a lot of time for one
more Nick Wishart how many goals will
Archie Thompson score this friday night
in the Melbourne Derby a league final I
don't know how many he'll score let's
say let's hope he scores three but this
is going to be fantastic I caught up
with some of the guys from melbourne
victory just last week and I was with
Melbourne City a few weeks before that
we can be really really proud that the
all game is so popular the beautiful
game is such a big part of our sporting
culture and I know my youngest son
Joseph who loves soccer started off
playing auskick now he got soccer you
can see just how important that is in
his little life and I families right
across the suburbs and regional Victoria
a touched by it and we've got such an
elite offering the best stadiums the
best teams it's a great game and just a
final plug on football the world game
football the international champions cup
starting in the middle of the year this
is going to be fantastic manchester city
real madrid and AS Roma this is going to
be blockbuster football the best of the
beautiful game in the world's most
livable city and sported capital Nick I
hope you there I really very much do so
I think this has been our first I i
assume won't be our last periscope press
conference a press conference with no
journalists that's that's a good thing
I'm sure I've done my best Ron Burgundy
impersonation possible it's great to
interact with people real people asking
real questions about the budget than
what it means for them thanks for your
feedback thanks for being part of this
and we look forward to seeing you again
soon