cyclists heading towards the Eastern
Freeway can choose to use either the
separated shared user path or the on
road cycling lane which transitions to a
separated off-road cycling lane just
before the existing bridge providing a
safe crossing over the Yarra River for
pedestrians and cyclists at the upgraded
Gera Boulevard intersection cyclists can
rejoin an on-road cycling lane towards
the eastern freeway and anniversary
trail or safely join yarrow Boulevard
new traffic lights and a pedestrian
crossing will provide safer
opportunities to cross the highway
cyclists can use a new underpass instead
of the 70 steps for convenient and
easier access to the main yarrow Trail