Last year, 37 Victorians were murdered by
the people they trusted the most.
And we failed every single one of them.
Family violence is a silent crime, deployed
by cowards behind closed doors.
It’s Australia’s number one law-and-order
issue – but it’s taken us too long to
admit it.
The numbers are staggering; the human cost
unacceptable.
And one thing is for certain: more of the
same policies will only mean more of the same
tragedies.
Well, now it’s time to change it all.
Today, Australia’s first Royal Commission
into Family Violence hands down its full and
final report.
This Commission received one thousand submissions.
It has given us thousands of pages of
answers – and a raft of recommendations
that will save Australian lives.
We will implement every single one of them.
We will overhaul our broken support system
from the bottom up.
We will punish the perpetrators of this violence,
we will listen to the people who survived
it, and we will change the culture that created
it.
In doing so, Victoria won’t just be leading
the nation.
We’ll be leading the world.
We have one chance, here.
And I refuse to look back in ten years’
time and admit that we could have done more
to save innocent lives.
The fact is we’ve failed enough already.
We’re going to get this right.
And we’re going to do it by listening to
the survivors, working with the professionals
who support them, and bringing the Victorian
people along with us, every step of the way.