These laws did not just punish homosexual
acts, they punished homosexual thought. They
had no place in a liberal democracy. They
have no place anywhere. The Victorian Parliament
and the Victorian Government were at fault.
For this, we are sorry. On behalf of this
house, we express our deepest regret. Speaker
– it’s never too late to put things right.
It’s never too late to say sorry – and
mean it.
That’s what brings us all to the heart of
our democracy today here in this Parliament where
over the course of decades, a powerful prejudice
was written into law.
A prejudice that ruined lives.
A prejudice that prevails in different ways,
even still.
That law was written in our name – as representatives,
and as Victorians.
And that law was enforced by the very democratic
system to which we call ourselves faithful.
So it is our responsibility to prove that
the Parliament that engineered this prejudice
can also be the Parliament that ends it.
That starts with acknowledging the offences
of the past admitting the failings of the
present and building a society for the future
that is strong and fair and just.
In doing so, Speaker, we’ll have shown this
moment to be no mere gesture.
In doing so, we’ll have proven that the
dignity and bravery of generations of Victorians
wasn’t simply for nought.
And that, I hope, will be the greatest comfort
of all.
Speaker, there is no more simple an acknowledgement
than this:
There was a time in our history when we turned
thousands of ordinary young men into criminals.
And it was profoundly and unimaginably wrong.
That such a thing could have occurred – once,
perhaps a century ago – would not surprise
most Victorians.
Well, Speaker, I hold here an article that reports
the random arrest of 15 men.
“Police Blitz Catches Homosexuals”, that’s what the
headline reads.
And said a police officer: “…we just seem
to find homosexuals loitering wherever we go.”
This was published in Melbourne’s biggest-selling
weekly newspaper – not 100 years ago, but in 1976.
A decade earlier, in 1967, a local paper said
that a dozen men would soon face court for
“morals offences”, and urged
the public to report homosexuals to the police
with a minimum of delay.
A generation earlier, in 1937, Judge MacIndoe
said John, a man in his 20s, was “not quite
sane”, and gaoled him for three months on
a charge of gross indecency.
In 1936, Jack, a working man from Sale, faced
a Melbourne court on the same charge – and
he was gaoled for ten years.
This, Speaker, is the society that we built.
And it would be easy to blame the courts,
or the media, or the police, or the public even.
It is easy for us to condemn their bigotry.
But the law required them to be bigoted.
And those laws were struck here, where I stand.
One of those laws even earned the label abominable, not something we use very often in our statute books.
In 1961 alone, 40 Victorian men were charged
with it.
In the same year, a minor offence was created
that shook just as many lives.
The penalty was $600 in today’s terms, or
one month imprisonment.
The charge? ‘Loitering for homosexual purposes’.
This was the offence used to justify that
random police blitz in 1976.
A witness said: “Young policemen were sent…to…entrap suspected homosexuals.”
“[Officers] dressed in swimwear…engaging
other men in conversation.”
“When the policeman was satisfied the person
was homosexual, an arrest was made.”
When we began this process, Speaker, I expected
to be offering an apology to people persecuted
for homosexual acts.
But it has become clear to me that the State
also persecuted against homosexual thought.
Loitering for homosexual purposes is a thought
crime.
And in one summer in 1976, in one location
alone, one hundred men were targeted under
this violation of thought; something for which
there was no possible defence.
All in our lifetimes, Speaker. All in our lifetimes.
And what’s more in our name.
Young people. Older people. Thousands and thousands
of people.
I suppose it’s rare when you can’t even
begin to conceive what was on the minds of
our forebears in this Place.
But I look back at those statutes and I am
dumbfounded.
I can’t possibly explain why we made these
laws, and clung to them, and fought for them.
For decades, we were obsessed with the private
mysteries of men.
And so we jailed them.
We harmed them. And, in turn, they harmed themselves.
Speaker, it is the first responsibility of
a Government to keep people safe.
But the Government didn’t keep LGBTI people
safe.
The Government invalidated their humanity
and cast them into a nightmare.
And those who live today are the survivors
of nothing less than a campaign of destruction,
led by the might of this State.
Speaker, I had the privilege of meeting with four of
those survivors recently.
One of them was Noel Tovey.
He was sent to Pentridge in 1951.
On more than one occasion in jail, he planned
his suicide.
“Max was singing an aria from La Traviata
when the police arrived,” he recalled in his book
I was very naive. I knew having sex with men
was against the law but I didn’t understand
why it was a crime.
At the hearing, the judge said, “You have
been charged with the abominable crime of
buggery. How do you plead?”
The maximum sentence was fifteen years.
Afterwards, only two people would talk to
me. I couldn’t…get a job. I was a known
criminal. And it’s ironic.
Eventually I would have been forgiven by everyone
if I had murdered Max, but no one could forgive
me for having sex with him.”
And Noel, in his own words, quite amazingly, in a sign of strength, calls himself “one of the lucky ones.”
I also met Terry Kennedy.
He was 18 years old when he was arrested.
“When I wanted to go overseas”, Terry
told me, “and when I wanted to start my
own business, there was always that dreaded
question:
“Have you ever been convicted of a criminal
offence?”
I lied, of course.
Then the phone rang…It was an inspector
from the St Kilda Police Station. He’d found
me out.
With a curse like that always lurking over
our heads, we always had to ask ourselves
[this question] – just how far can I go
today?”
That’s the sort of question which, in some
form or another, must have been asked by almost
every single LGBTI person.
And it is still asked today – by teenagers in
the schoolyard; by adults in the family home.
Yes, the law was unjust, but it is wrong to
think its only victims were those who faced
its sanction.
The fact is: these laws cast a dark and paralysing
pall over everyone who ever felt like they
were different.
The fact is: these laws represented nothing
less than official, state-sanctioned homophobia.
And we wonder why, Speaker – we wonder why
gay and lesbian and bi and trans teenagers
are still the target of a red, hot hatred.
We wonder why hundreds of thousands of Australians
are still formally excluded from something
as basic and decent as a formal celebration
of love.
And we wonder why so many people are still
forced to drape their lives in shame.
Shame: that deeply personal condition, described
by Peter McEwan as “the feeling of not being
good enough.”
Peter was arrested in 1967.
He soon fled overseas to escape that time in his life.
The fourth man I spoke with last week, Tom
Anderson, met his own private terror when
he was 14.
For weeks, he was routinely sexually assaulted
by his employer, his boss – a man in his 40s.
His parents, in all good faith, took Tom down
to the local police station to make a formal statement
and get his employer, this predator, charged.
And he was.
But so was Tom.
This child victim of sexual assault was charged
with one count of buggery and two counts of
gross indecency.
Can you believe, Speaker, that the year was
1977?
Today, Tom carries with him a quiet bravery
that is hard to put into words.
And he told me about the time – one day,
just a few years ago – when his home was
burgled.
“I’m a grown man”, he said, “but the
moment the police came around to inspect the
house, and I opened the door…I became that
14-year-old boy again.”
“I couldn’t talk. I was frozen. I was
a grown man and I couldn’t talk.”
This was life for innocent people like Tom.
We told them they were fugitives living outside
the law.
We gave them no safe place to find themselves
– or find each other.
And we made sure they couldn’t trust a soul. Not even their family.
A life like that. What do you think that does
to a human being?
What do you think it does to their ability
to find purpose, to hold themselves with confidence
to be happy, to be social, to be free?
Don’t tell me that these laws were simply
a suppression of sex.
This was a suppression of spirit.
A denial of love.
And it lives on, today.
While the laws were terminated in the 1980s,
they still remain next to the names of so many men.
Most of them are now gone, but a criminal
conviction engraved upon their place in history.
I can inform the House and all honourable members that six men have now successfully applied to expunge these
convictions from their record.
Many more have begun the process.
This won’t erase the injustice, but it is
an accurate statement of what I believe today:
That these convictions should never have happened.
That the charges will be deleted, as if they
had never existed.
And that their subjects can call themselves,
once again, law-abiding Victorians.
Expungement is one thing, but these victims
won’t find their salvation in this alone.
They are each and every one of them owed hope.
And all four of the men I met told me they
only began to find that hope when they met
people who were just like them.
Peter McEwan – back in the country, and
emerging from years of shame – started meeting
weekly with some gay friends at university
in 1972.
“We realised we were all outlaws together,”
he said, “and we learnt to say that we are
good”.
“We learnt to say ‘black is beautiful,
women are strong – and gay is good.’”
“Once I learnt I was good, it led me to
question everyone who said I was evil and
sick.”
“Gay men had taken on board the shame. Through
each other we found our pride.”
Then he paused for a second — and I will carry this with me forever — he paused for a second and he said to me:
“Pride is the opposite of shame.”
He’s right.
Pride is not a cold acceptance; it’s a celebration.
It’s about wearing your colours and baring
your character.
The mere expression of pride was an act of
sheer defiance.
These people we speak about – they weren’t
just fighting for the right to be equal.
They were fighting for the right to be different.
And I want everyone in this state, young or
old, to know that you, too, have that right.
You were born with that right.
And being who you are is good enough for me
– and it’s good enough for all of us.
Here in Victoria, equality is not negotiable.
Here, you can be different from everybody
else, but still be treated the same as everybody else.
Because we believe in fairness.
We believe in honesty, too – so we have
to acknowledge this:
For the time being, we can’t promise things
will be easy.
Tomorrow, a young bloke will get hurt.
Tomorrow, a parent will turn their back on
their child.
Tomorrow, a loving couple and their beautiful
baby will be met with a stare of contempt.
Tomorrow, a trans woman will be turned away
from a job interview.
And tomorrow, a gay teenager will think about
ending his own life.
That’s the truth.
There is so much more we need to do to make
things right.
Until then, we can’t promise things will
be easy. Far from it.
We can’t guarantee that everyone in your
life will respect the way you want to live it.
And we can’t expect you to make what must
be a terrifying plunge until you know the
time is right.
But just know that whenever that time comes,
you have a Government and a Parliament that’s on your side.
You have a Government that is trying to make
the state a safer place – in the classroom,
in the workplace.
You have a Government that is trying to eradicate
a culture of bullying and harassment so that
the next generation of children are never
old enough to experience it.
You have a Government that sees these indisputable
statistics – of LGBTI self-harm, of suicide
– and commits to their complete upheaval.
You have a Government that believes you’re
free to be who you are, and to marry the person
you love.
And you have a Government that knows just
one life saved is worth all the effort.
Speaker, as part of this process, I learnt
that two women were convicted for offensive
behaviour in the 1970s for holding hands – on
a tram.
So let me finish by saying this:
If you are a member of the LGBTI community,
and there’s someone in your life that you
love – a partner or a friend – then do
me a favour:
Next time you’re on a tram in Melbourne,
hold their hand.
Do it with pride and defiance.
Because you have that freedom.
And here in the progressive capital of our nation, I can
think of nothing more Victorian than that.
Speaker, it’s been a life of struggle for
generations of Victorians.
As representatives, we take full responsibility.
We criminalised homosexual thoughts and deeds.
We validated homophobic words and acts.
And we set the tone for a society that ruthlessly
punished the different – with a short sentence
in prison, and a life sentence of shame.
From now on, that shame is ours.
This Parliament and this Government are to
be formally held to account for designing
a culture of darkness and shame.
And those who faced its sanction, and lived
in fear, are to be formally recognised for
their relentless pursuit of freedom and love.
It all started here, and it all ends here, too.
To our knowledge, no jurisdiction in the world
has ever offered a full and formal apology
for laws like these.
So please, let these words rest forever in
our records:
On behalf of the Parliament, the Government
and the people of Victoria.
For the laws we passed.
And the lives we ruined.
And the standards we set.
We are so sorry. Humbly, deeply, sorry.