Just two degrees.
It might not sound like a lot – but a two
degree increase in global temperatures would
change everything.
An extra two degrees means we risk more extreme
weather, heat waves, rising sea levels and drought.
If it's to be stopped, every nation and
every government has a role to play.
That begins with reducing our emissions.
We have a plan, but we need your help too.
TAKE2 is Victoria's commitment to reach
zero emissions by 2050.
The Victorian Government will be doing its
share with targets for 2020 and every five
years after that.
We'll make the Climate Change Act the strongest
in Australia.
We'll build a clean energy economy, because supporting
renewable energy means supporting jobs.
And, of course, we'll help households and businesses to
save energy and save money.
But TAKE2 is about collective climate change
action.
That means all of us – individuals, communities,
businesses – we all have a responsibility.
It's time to get real about climate change –
for this generation, and the generations to come.
We need to do more.
And we need to do it now.
It's time for us all to TAKE2, at take2.vic.gov.au