Melbourne's scored a major coup with New York's
Museum of Modern Art to send some of its famous
works to the NGV. Daniel Andrews helped secure
the deal, which he believes will break gallery
attendance records. State political reporter
Andrew Lund is travelling with him.
New York's Museum of Modern Art – home to the
likes of Van Gogh, Cézanne, Dalí and Lichtenstein.
This is one of the greatest collections in
the world.
In a coup made possible by some
personal intervention from Premier Daniel Andrews,
150 of those works are set to travel to Melbourne.
This is a roll call of the greatest names
and the greatest works in contemporary art
and they're all coming to Melbourne.
They'll be on display at the NGV from June to October 2018 as part of the Winter Masterpieces.
Many of the works rarely travel.
Loans that are literally painful to make because we have
an audience here that comes to see certain
paintings and many of those will be in Melbourne,
so we hope they will travel there to see them.
The Premier is hoping the collection will
prove a tourism boom. This will break all
This will break all records. This will be such a significant show.
This will get several hundred thousand people easily.
Earlier, Daniel Andrews was guest
of honour at the New York Stock Exchange for
a briefing on the art of making money. The
Premier used the visit to tout for investment
and highlight Victoria's infrastructure agenda,
in particular the Metro Rail Tunnel and
Western Distributor, which are both out to
market. But while Daniel Andrews had poll
position for the opening, it was Indy 500
winner Alexander Rossi given the honour of
ringing the bell.
In New York, Andrew Lund, Nine News.