Today, I'm really pleased to announce that
an expression of interest for early important
construction works to move power, water, storm
water, gas and a whole range of other services
to relocate those services from the Melbourne
Metro alignment, that expression of interest
will go to the market tomorrow. We expect
that program of works will be in the order
of around $300 million – of course there's
a tender process to be gone through, but that
will be the order of it. It's a very significant
investment and it just shows that we are wasting
no time at all. Not one day will be wasted
in delivering a world-class public transport
system for the world's most livable city.
Protecting around 150 different sorts of utility
services underneath the ground is so important
to do this work now, to get this expression
of interest out to market now, to see these
works undertaken in 2017, but most critically
to see these works completed by 2018 so we
can hit the ground running with the major
construction program that is scheduled to
start in 2018. It's a big job, it's going
to mean there will be some disruption, particularly
in and around the areas of the portal entrances,
but we have to do this now and provide this
program of works so that we can see Melbourne
Metro up and running.