there's something else I want to talk to
you about today something that's so
wrong it obscures everything else that
is right and that's family violence I
should let you know that what I'm about
to say may be distressing for some
family violence is a national emergency
family violence ruins lives family
violence kills all of you in this room
know someone you know a victim and you
may know them well but you might not
know who I'm heartened of course by the
many campaigns that have bought
awareness to it but these campaigns have
told us something else as well awareness
means little if the system is broken and
our system is thousands of dedicated
workers and volunteers dozens of
important services they work hard to
make things better but the system is
still broken it doesn't protect the
vulnerable and it doesn't punish the
guilty it's failing we won't fix it
until we admit it now I may be
criticized for saying that and I don't
care I simply don't we expect victims to
make a deeply personal and terrifying
leap to come forward to seek protection
but we're not doing our bit we're not
there to catch them when they make that
leap instead those seeking help and
assistance fall into endless waiting
lists a support network that's
underfunded a police force that's under
pressure and intervention orders that
often mean nothing it's a betrayal
that's the reason why we always witness
these tragedies hours too late on our
evening news played before us and an
audience of millions news stories filled
with old photographs and the thoughtful
words of loved ones for short films of
our greatest failure so many families
have met tragedy we must remember them
and we must remember to those in newer
relationships who might be slowly losing
their freedom slowly losing themselves
too many are later described as the
victims of unexpected isolated incidents
well there's nothing unexpected or
isolated about it this is a vicious
pattern think about some of these words
from survivors we weren't allowed to cry
inside the house I couldn't leave he'd
taken my keys gradually he made me
believe that I had no friends he thought
it was what husbands were allowed to do
these words tell us that Family Violence
can come in any form it can creep into
any home it can happen to anyone I'll
never forget how I felt on that routine
weekday evening when I heard what had
happened on a suburban cricket ground to
an ordinary boy who loved his mum and
loved his dad when I got home that night
when I got home that night all I wanted
to do was wake up my kids and hold them
close nothing is more honest than the
loyalty of a child and nothing hurts
more than its betrayal 15 children known
to DHS 15
vulnerable children died this year and
family violence was a factor in 12 of
those tragedies it's unthinkable when
family violence is committed against
women and their children it diminishes
us all because it is our problem and it
is a crime it's forty percent of police
work it's the leading contributor to
death and disability in Australian women
under 45 one woman is murdered by her
current or former partner each and every
week one in four children witness
violence against a parent and that's a
form of violence in itself we have to
admit that if women and their children
were being systematically tormented by
total strangers we would be quick to act
we would do more instead tonight women
and their children will huddle in sparse
hotel rooms and refuges briefly away
from the violence but never further away
from a loving and caring home tonight
sons and daughters will lock themselves
in their rooms their perception of the
most formative adult relationship in
their young lives forever scarred
forever changed tonight Victoria Police
will respond to around a hundred
incidents of violence and abuse doing
the best they can without the resources
they need next week intervention orders
will be made and intervention orders
will be breached men will be referred to
behavior change programs in reality
they'll be referred to waiting lists
lists that are longer than is safe
longer than is acceptable tomorrow many
victims will be too scared to call out
for help others will be too ashamed some
will take the leap
but all will be one way or another let
down by a system that simply cannot cope
and cannot protect for some there may be
no tomorrow and what are the politicians
doing well we're posing for photographs
and we're wearing a ribbon but we're not
asking the really hard questions some
people think the chief duty of a
government is to maintain law and order
well the biggest law and order issue in
our state is unfolding inside our homes
when we see it on the TV we don't know
what to say the truth is we don't know
what to do either we don't have all the
answers friends I cannot promise to keep
every woman and her children safe I
cannot promise to make sure every family
is free of violence but I'm prepared to
try it's time
it is time to change it all that's why
today I announce that a Victorian Labour
government will establish Australia's
first royal commission into family
violence
and nothing will be off limits the
Family Violence Royal Commission will
examine our system from the ground up it
will investigate criminal law
Corrections and the courts it will look
at support services the health system
alcohol and drug treatment it will look
at refuges housing and education and of
course it will look at the resources and
the tools that are available to our
dedicated Victoria Police a panel of
survivors and support provider's will
advise and assist the Royal Commission
it will begin its work early next year
reporting to Parliament and to all
Victorians by the end of 2015 and a
Victorian Labour government will
implement its recommendations
the Commission will take time but there
are some things that simply cannot wait
that's why I intend to make more
announcements on this critical issue
that's why back in December I appointed
a dedicated standalone Shadow Minister
for the Prevention of family violence
our colleague and friend Daniel Green
that's why friends that's why this
ministry in government will be in the
Department of premier and cabinet at the
heart of our government and at the
center at the center of our agenda
that's why I two of the state as part of
our labor cares program meeting with
those affected by family violence and
the people who support them they must be
acknowledged the many organizations and
individuals who work so hard people like
Fiona McCormick a domestic-violence
Victoria
and of course the dedicated men and
women of Victoria Police these people
these Victorians save lives every day
the Royal Commission will honor their
work the Royal Commission will give us
the answers we desperately need just a
few weeks ago I visited my old school
and I told the students they're the most
important thing I've ever learned if you
have the opportunity then you have the
obligation we can do more and we must do
more on this important issue because
once every so often a genuine crisis
erupts in the most powerful way
imaginable when that happens our
obligation to do something becomes
overwhelming friends that time has come
I will never forget what happened a few
months ago to an eleven-year-old boy on
a cricket ground and I'll never forget
meeting with his remarkable mum his
remarkable mum Rosie and hearing her
story she is the face of courage in this
country when we hear the anguish in one
family we must listen long enough to
hear the deafening whisper in thousands
more we hear it and we are going to do
something about it
we're going to do something about it
because the time has come to put people
first thank you very much
you