My name's Krystal Wright and I'm 27 years old
and I was diagnosed with stage two breast cancer
in November last year, 2015.
Obviously being 27 and being diagnosed with cancer was quite a shock.
I've heard nothing but fantastic stories of the staff and the doctors,
so it was easy to decide to get Peter Mac to help me out.
SHERENE: The interaction I think between scientists and clinicians are really important
to help drive forward the science and to try and bring that to patients.
We can be right there with the patient and literally come up to the 12th floor to process the sample.
And then when we process the sample, we hope to understand what's making that breast cancer grow.
And we can potentially then enrol that patient onto a clinical trial.
And we're really the only centre in the southern hemisphere that has this capability.
KRYSTAL: My team of surgeons and oncologists, nurses,
they make it so much easier.
It's not as daunting.
Yeah, it's still scary, not knowing what to expect,
but having a team that everyone gets it makes the experience so much easier.
BOON: When I see Krystal in 10 years' time and
she's well and healthy with a family,
I think that would be the best reward I could get.