I'm November 25 2013 we inherited a tape
system on its knees and a training
system eternal I'm determined to bring
stability to our training sector to
rebuild our hopes and ensure that all
Victorians have the opportunity to get
high priority skills to a high quality
job and to add to the productivity of
our state there are far too many young
people leaving school only to find
themselves on the trigger of
unemployment disillusioned with rach
hope and in despair I'm determined to
change that I'm going to provide
training and skills and job
opportunities to take them off that
treadmill and put them on the foot path
to success