The earth is getting warmer.
Our climate is changing rapidly.
To slow down this change,
we all must pledge to TAKE2.
TAKE2 is Victoria's climate change pledge to keep
the temperature rise to under two degrees by 2050.
It's time for us all to play our part
in Victoria's action on climate change.
I will take two minutes to
keep the Dandenongs healthy.
I will take two so the waterfront doesn't rise.
I'll take two for my grandkids' future,
to create new jobs in clean energy,
for small business.
I'll take two to keep our seasonal local produce in the same seasons.
I'll take two for our farmers.
I'll take two to keep football in winter.
I will take two and commit to doing
my part to reduce Victoria's emissions.
To keep the temperature rise to under two
degrees, we must all take action.
Pledge to TAKE2 now at take2.vic.gov.au.