Today, we're going to do something very
important.
Homosexuality used to be illegal in Victoria.
Homosexual acts were routinely and ruthlessly
punished by the government, the police and
the courts.
Young men were sent to jail, sometimes for
up to fifteen years.
Others were fined, charged, sentenced, sacked,
shunned – and ruined.
It was state-sanctioned homophobia.
And this wasn't a century ago – this was
in my lifetime, possibly in yours.
Today, we're going to apologise on behalf
of parliaments and governments past for
the laws we made, the lives we wrecked.
It'll be the first full and formal apology
of its kind anywhere in the world.
And it won't make things right, but it's the
right thing to do, because in our state – equality
is not negotiable.
We'll try to get the video of the apology
or a transcript up on my Facebook
as soon as it’s done.
Or you can tune in to the Victorian Parliament
website at 2pm to watch it live.
This is more than a simple gesture – it's
a powerful statement of responsibility.
Legal homophobia began here, in this Parliament.
It has to end here, too.