Melbourne's new Metro Tunnel will free up
space in the city loop so we can run more
trains in and out of the CBD.
Works on the biggest public transport project
in Victoria's history are underway.
Up to 100 utilities including gas, power and
telecommunications services need to be relocated
or protected.
Some changes to the road network will be required.
A number of network enhancement projects will
be delivered in conjunction with existing
Vic Roads initiatives to accommodate diverted
traffic while Metro Tunnel is built.
We'll start excavating station shafts and
clearing areas next to Swanston Street to
prepare for the construction of the two new
underground city stations.
The face of our city will change from early
2017 as we dig 11 storys below the CBD.
Metro Tunnel will create the international-style
train system we need.